So, hi everyone, my name is Shengyu Chen and this is Eric Huang, and today we're going
안녕하세요 여러분. 제 이름은 Shengyu Chen이고 이쪽은 Eric Huang입니다. 오늘 우리는
to present multi-model models pre-training.
다중 모델 모델 사전 훈련을 제시합니다.
So a quick overview of what we are going to cover today.
그럼 오늘 다룰 내용에 대해 간단히 살펴보겠습니다.
So first we're going to talk about some introduction and background, specifically where I talk
먼저 소개와 배경, 특히 제가 이야기하는 부분에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
about multi-model representations and multi-model tasks.
다중 모델 표현 및 다중 모델 작업에 대해 설명합니다.
And then following that we're going to talk about seven different multi-model pre-training
그런 다음 7가지 다중 모델 사전 학습에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
papers and we group them by their main contributions.
논문을 주요 기여도별로 분류합니다.
And then at the end we're going to have a review and summarization section.
그런 다음 마지막에는 검토 및 요약 섹션을 갖게 됩니다.
And please save your question at the end of each paper because we have a lot to cover
그리고 다루어야 할 내용이 많기 때문에 각 보고서 끝 부분에 질문을 저장해 두십시오.
today.
오늘.
So first introduction and background.
그럼 첫 번째 소개와 배경을 살펴보겠습니다.
Most of multi-model representations, multi-modality is a scientific study of heterogeneous and
다중 모델 표현의 대부분인 다중 양식은 이질적이고
interconnected data and by heterogeneous we mean that it can be like task image, audio
상호 연결된 데이터이며 이질적이라는 것은 작업 이미지, 오디오와 같을 수 있음을 의미합니다.
and different format of the data.
그리고 데이터의 형식이 다릅니다.
And our goal is to represent and summarize multi-model data in a joint representation
그리고 우리의 목표는 다중 모델 데이터를 공동 표현으로 표현하고 요약하는 것입니다.
such that the complementary information is preserved in the joint representation and
보완적인 정보가 공동 표현에 보존되도록
the redundant parts of the multi-modalities are filtered out.
다중 양식의 중복 부분은 필터링됩니다.
So here's a visualization of three different modalities, namely that the task image and
그래서 여기에 세 가지 다른 양식의 시각화가 있습니다. 즉, 작업 이미지와
the audio, they can be represented in the joint space.
오디오는 공동 공간에서 표현될 수 있습니다.
And today's presentation will only focus on vision language pre-training.
그리고 오늘 프레젠테이션에서는 비전 언어 사전 훈련에만 중점을 둘 것입니다.
So we're not going to cover about, for example, the audio data.
따라서 우리는 예를 들어 오디오 데이터에 대해서는 다루지 않을 것입니다.
And some tasks for multi-model models.
다중 모델 모델에 대한 몇 가지 작업도 있습니다.
So there are two different, two main different tasks.
따라서 두 가지 주요 작업이 있습니다.
One is the understanding, the other one is the generation task.
하나는 이해이고, 다른 하나는 생성 작업이다.
So for understanding we can have image text retrieval.
따라서 이해를 위해 이미지 텍스트 검색을 사용할 수 있습니다.
So this is basically predict whether a given image text pair is aligned or not.
따라서 이것은 기본적으로 주어진 이미지 텍스트 쌍이 정렬되었는지 여부를 예측합니다.
And then we have the natural language visual reasoning and LBR.
그리고 자연어 시각적 추론과 LBR이 있습니다.
So given a pair of image and text, we need to determine whether the text statement is
따라서 이미지와 텍스트 쌍이 주어지면 텍스트 문이 다음과 같은지 여부를 결정해야 합니다.
true about the images.
이미지에 대해서는 사실입니다.
So here's an example.
여기에 예가 있습니다.
We have two set of pictures and the description is that there are two trains in total, traveling
우리는 두 세트의 사진을 가지고 있으며 설명에는 총 두 대의 열차가 여행하고 있다고 나와 있습니다.
the same direction.
같은 방향.
So the talking bit is correct, one is wrong.
그러니까 얘기하는 부분은 맞고 하나는 틀렸어요.
And then another task in understanding is the visual question answering VQA in short.
그리고 이해의 또 다른 작업은 간단히 말해서 VQA에 대답하는 시각적 질문입니다.
So given the image and the question, the model needs to select the correct answer from a
따라서 이미지와 질문이 주어지면 모델은 다음 중 정답을 선택해야 합니다.
multi-choice list.
다중 선택 목록.
For example, in this picture you can ask question like, is the tray on top of the table black
예를 들어, 이 사진에서 다음과 같은 질문을 할 수 있습니다. 테이블 위에 있는 트레이는 검은색인가요?
or light brown?
아니면 밝은 갈색?
We expect the model to answer light brown.
우리는 모델이 연한 갈색으로 대답할 것으로 예상합니다.
And for the generation task, mainly the image captioning.
그리고 생성 작업에서는 주로 이미지 캡션을 작성합니다.
So we want the model to generate a natural language description about the content of
따라서 우리는 모델이 콘텐츠에 대한 자연어 설명을 생성하기를 원합니다.
an image.
이미지.
So here's an example.
여기에 예가 있습니다.
We want the model to generate, for example, like a man with yellow tie looks concerned.
예를 들어, 노란색 넥타이를 매는 남자가 걱정하는 표정을 짓는 것처럼 모델을 생성하려고 합니다.
And we can also formulate the VQA as an open-ended VQA and then it becomes a generation task.
또한 VQA를 개방형 VQA로 공식화하여 생성 작업이 될 수도 있습니다.
And then just some history about the BLP methods prior to 2020.
그리고 2020년 이전의 BLP 방법에 대한 몇 가지 역사입니다.
For example, the visual bird that simply concatenate the visual region features and the word embeddings
예를 들어, 시각적 영역 특징과 단어 임베딩을 단순히 연결하는 시각적 새
of pair tags as input to a transformer model and then use self-attention to implicitly
쌍 태그를 변환기 모델에 대한 입력으로 사용한 다음 self-attention을 사용하여 암시적으로
align elements of tasks, tags, and image regions.
작업, 태그 및 이미지 영역의 요소를 정렬합니다.
So here's an example.
여기에 예가 있습니다.
We have some object detectors to track the visual features as in here.
여기에서와 같이 시각적 특징을 추적하는 몇 가지 객체 감지기가 있습니다.
And then we have a caption, meaning to allow you to know the field, you can tag it in together
그런 다음 캡션이 있습니다. 즉, 필드를 알 수 있도록 함께 태그를 지정할 수 있습니다.
to them through the platform and block.
플랫폼과 블록을 통해 그들에게 다가갑니다.
And then we can add different VQA functions as an output to train the models.
그런 다음 다양한 VQA 기능을 출력으로 추가하여 모델을 학습할 수 있습니다.
And then we hope that through self-attention we can learn, for example, a heat map between
그런 다음 self-attention을 통해 예를 들어 사이의 히트 맵을 배울 수 있기를 바랍니다.
the visual features, between the visual features, and the track features.
시각적 특징과 트랙 특징 사이의 시각적 특징.
So we're going to begin to talk about our papers today.
그래서 오늘은 우리 논문에 대해 이야기를 시작하겠습니다.
So the first group is about the visual representation improvement.
첫 번째 그룹은 시각적 표현 개선에 관한 것입니다.
The first paper we're going to talk about is OSCAR.
우리가 이야기할 첫 번째 논문은 OSCAR입니다.
Semantics aligned pre-training for visual language tasks.
의미론은 시각적 언어 작업을 위한 사전 훈련을 조정했습니다.
The main contribution about this paper is the semantic alignments between text and images
이 논문의 주요 기여는 텍스트와 이미지 간의 의미론적 정렬입니다.
using object tags.
객체 태그를 사용합니다.
So as we can see before, the challenges about visual bird is one, ambiguity, the image region
앞서 볼 수 있듯이 시각적 새에 대한 과제는 하나, 모호함, 이미지 영역입니다.
overlapping at different positions results in ambiguities for the extracted visual embeddings.
서로 다른 위치에서 겹치면 추출된 시각적 임베딩이 모호해집니다.
The second challenge is the lack of explicit alignments.
두 번째 과제는 명시적인 정렬이 부족하다는 것입니다.
So there is no explicitly labeled alignments between regions of the objects in the image text pairs.
따라서 이미지 텍스트 쌍의 개체 영역 간에는 명시적으로 레이블이 지정된 정렬이 없습니다.
So the motivation of OSCAR is to use salient objects.
따라서 OSCAR의 동기는 두드러진 개체를 사용하는 것입니다.
So they can be accurately detected by the object detectors.
따라서 물체 감지기로 정확하게 감지할 수 있습니다.
And they are often mentioned in the paired text.
그리고 그들은 짝을 이루는 텍스트에서 자주 언급됩니다.
They can be used as the anchor points for learning semantic alignments between image
이미지 간의 의미적 정렬을 학습하기 위한 기준점으로 사용할 수 있습니다.
region features and the word embeddings.
지역 특징과 단어 임베딩.
So here is an example of a dog sitting on a couch.
여기 소파에 앉아 있는 개가 있는 예가 있습니다.
So here dog and couch, they are salient objects because they can be detected in the images
여기 개와 소파는 이미지에서 감지될 수 있기 때문에 눈에 띄는 개체입니다.
and they are also included in the text.
그리고 그것들은 본문에도 포함되어 있습니다.
So how they extract the anchor points.
그래서 앵커 포인트를 추출하는 방법입니다.
So the OSCAR authors, they extract the visual embeddings first using the faster RCNN
따라서 OSCAR 작성자는 더 빠른 RCNN을 사용하여 먼저 시각적 임베딩을 추출합니다.
to extract the visual semantics of each regions as v prime and z.
각 영역의 시각적 의미를 v 프라임 및 z로 추출합니다.
v prime is a region feature and z is the region position.
v prime은 영역 기능이고 z는 영역 위치입니다.
They concatenate them together to form a position sensitive region feature vector
위치 감지 영역 특징 벡터를 형성하기 위해 이들을 서로 연결합니다.
and they use a trainable linear projection to transfer the v prime and z into v
그리고 그들은 v 프라임과 z를 v로 전송하기 위해 훈련 가능한 선형 투영을 사용합니다.
which is a vector of hidden dimension h.
이는 숨겨진 차원 h의 벡터입니다.
And here in this graph, we can see the reader features their print source.
여기 이 그래프에서 독자가 인쇄 소스를 특징으로 하는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
And then they extract the word embeddings.
그런 다음 단어 임베딩을 추출합니다.
So first, they extract the tag embeddings using the faster RCNN.
먼저 더 빠른 RCNN을 사용하여 태그 임베딩을 추출합니다.
So after they extract the visual objects, they can also get the text and they feed the tag to
따라서 시각적 객체를 추출한 후에는 텍스트도 얻을 수 있고 태그를 피드에 제공할 수도 있습니다.
the bird tokenizer to get word tokens queued which is also h-dimensional.
역시 h차원인 단어 토큰을 대기열에 추가하는 새 토크나이저입니다.
And here you can see the tag seeker data for each sector as compared to the region embeddings.
여기에서는 지역 임베딩과 비교하여 각 섹터의 태그 탐색자 데이터를 볼 수 있습니다.
And then they use bird tokenizers to extract the text or the caption
그런 다음 새 토크나이저를 사용하여 텍스트나 캡션을 추출합니다.
into text embeddings w, the embedded text into word tokens w which is also a h-dimensional vector.
텍스트 임베딩 w로, 삽입된 텍스트를 역시 h차원 벡터인 단어 토큰 w로 만듭니다.
And then what they do is simply concatenate all of them.
그리고 그들이 하는 일은 단순히 그것들을 모두 연결하는 것입니다.
So here we have the caption tokens, we have the tokens from the other tag,
여기에 캡션 토큰이 있고 다른 태그의 토큰이 있습니다.
we have the embeddings from our images.
우리는 이미지로부터 임베딩을 갖고 있습니다.
And then after they put them together, we can look at different embeddings from two different views.
그런 다음 두 가지를 합친 후에는 두 가지 다른 관점에서 다양한 임베딩을 볼 수 있습니다.
One is the modality view which shows here.
하나는 여기에 표시된 양식 보기입니다.
So in modality view, we can view the text modality which is a bird token in the text modality.
따라서 양식 보기에서는 텍스트 양식의 새 토큰인 텍스트 양식을 볼 수 있습니다.
And then we can combine the region features and the associated object text as an image modality.
그런 다음 지역 특징과 관련 개체 텍스트를 이미지 양식으로 결합할 수 있습니다.
And our goal is to distinguish the representations between a text and an image.
그리고 우리의 목표는 텍스트와 이미지의 표현을 구별하는 것입니다.
We can also look at them from a dictionary view.
우리는 사전적 관점에서도 그것들을 볼 수 있습니다.
So in dictionary view, we have linguistic semantic space where we put the word tokens
따라서 사전 보기에는 단어 토큰을 넣는 언어적 의미 공간이 있습니다.
and the object text together and then we put the image region features separately.
그리고 객체 텍스트를 함께 넣은 다음 이미지 영역 기능을 별도로 배치합니다.
And then our goal is to distinguish the semantic spaces between text and images.
그리고 우리의 목표는 텍스트와 이미지 사이의 의미 공간을 구별하는 것입니다.
So to design the loss for modality view, we have, recall that we have text modality as in w.
따라서 양식 보기에 대한 손실을 설계하기 위해 w와 같은 텍스트 양식이 있다는 것을 기억합니다.
And then we concatenate the object tag and region feature as h prime.
그런 다음 객체 태그와 영역 기능을 h 소수로 연결합니다.
And then Oscar pollute the h prime such that it contains a set of images where 50% of the tags
그런 다음 오스카는 태그의 50%가 포함된 이미지 세트를 포함하도록 h 프라임을 오염시킵니다.
are replaced with different tags.
다른 태그로 대체됩니다.
And they train a binary classifier f to predict whether the image text modality pair
그리고 이미지 텍스트 양식 쌍이 ​​다음과 같은지 여부를 예측하기 위해 이진 분류기 f를 훈련시킵니다.
contains the original image or the polluting ones.
원본 이미지나 오염된 이미지가 포함되어 있습니다.
And then we can have a contrastive loss which simply measures how good the binary classifier is.
그런 다음 이진 분류기가 얼마나 좋은지 간단히 측정하는 대조 손실을 가질 수 있습니다.
And our goal is to address the word embedding space where a text is similar to its paired images
그리고 우리의 목표는 텍스트가 쌍을 이루는 이미지와 유사한 단어 임베딩 공간을 해결하는 것입니다.
and this similar to the polluted images.
이는 오염된 이미지와 유사합니다.
So this is the loss for modality view.
이것이 양식적 관점의 손실입니다.
And then they design loss for dictionary view.
그리고 사전 보기에 대한 손실을 설계합니다.
So in this to recall, we concatenate the word token embedding and the object tag embedding as h.
따라서 기억해야 할 점은 토큰 임베딩이라는 단어와 객체 태그 임베딩을 h로 연결한 것입니다.
And then region feature is treated separately.
그런 다음 지역 특성을 별도로 처리합니다.
And then for this one, they replace 15% of the tokens in h is written in h prime.
그리고 이것을 위해 그들은 h에 있는 토큰의 15%를 h 프라임으로 대체합니다.
Of the tokens in h is replaced with a mask token which is very similar to what Bert did.
h의 토큰 중 Bert가 수행한 것과 매우 유사한 마스크 토큰으로 대체됩니다.
So similar to mask language models like Bert, we want to predict the mask text tokens h
Bert와 같은 마스크 언어 모델과 유사하게 마스크 텍스트 토큰 h를 예측하려고 합니다.
based on surrounding text tokens and all the other image features v.
주변 텍스트 토큰 및 기타 모든 이미지 기능을 기반으로 v.
And then we have the mask token loss.
그리고 마스크 토큰 손실이 발생합니다.
So our goal is to ground the word embedding in the region context.
따라서 우리의 목표는 지역 컨텍스트에 임베딩이라는 단어를 기반으로 하는 것입니다.
Yes.
예.
Yeah.
응.
Um
하나
That's the point. Um
그게 요점입니다. 음
I think what they did is to mainly like the mask, uh, the word, uh, so the image, uh,
제 생각에는 그들이 주로 마스크, 어, 단어, 어, 이미지를 좋아했던 것 같아요.
No, I mean, like, you know, like, like, like this part, uh, so for the gift,
아니, 내 말은, 그러니까, 이 부분처럼, 어, 선물용으로
they give the, uh, the image region and the object tag.
그들은, 어, 이미지 영역과 객체 태그를 제공합니다.
And they basically they want you to use this one.
그리고 그들은 기본적으로 여러분이 이것을 사용하기를 원합니다.
You want to predict what, uh,
당신은 무엇을 예측하고 싶은지, 어,
for each image.
각 이미지마다.
Each image you use.
사용하는 각 이미지.
Each image makes the language that's between
각 이미지는 그 사이에 있는 언어를 만듭니다.
I have seen in California.
캘리포니아에서 본 적이 있어요.
Yeah.
응.
Um, like 15% or in h,
음, 15%나 시간 단위로요.
h is w and q.
h는 w와 q입니다.
Yeah.
응.
Yeah, I'm not sure, like, probably different than the other.
네, 잘 모르겠습니다. 아마도 다른 것과는 다를 것 같습니다.
Um,
하나,
I guess a little piece.
작은 조각인 것 같아요.
So like only one of the objects.
그래서 개체 중 하나만 좋아합니다.
Yeah.
응.
At that case, it's, uh, if both of them are dropped, I guess they need some, like, uh,
그렇다면, 어, 둘 다 떨어뜨리면 뭔가가 필요할 것 같은데요, 어,
detailed, uh, to, to help with the watch.
자세히, 어, 시계 작업을 돕기 위해요.
To be maintained like the same color.
같은 색상처럼 유지됩니다.
To see the object text and the image content.
개체 텍스트와 이미지 내용을 보려면
Like, I was, let's see what response would be one.
예를 들어, 어떤 반응이 나올지 봅시다.
I think they do.
제 생각에는 그렇습니다.
Yeah.
응.
So maybe that's another way to help the lady.
그럼 그게 그 부인을 돕는 또 다른 방법일 수도 있겠네요.
And then, uh, we put both laws together, uh, and then we have the total pre-training laws.
그리고 나서, 어, 우리는 두 법칙을 합치고, 어, 그러면 우리는 전체 사전 훈련 법칙을 갖게 됩니다.
Uh, the trainable parameters are the linear projection metrics, uh, that can map the region
어, 훈련 가능한 매개변수는 지역을 매핑할 수 있는 선형 투영 측정항목입니다.
features, uh, to the same dimension as the, uh, word embeddings.
어, 단어 임베딩과 동일한 차원의 기능입니다.
And they also train a bird.
그리고 그들은 또한 새를 훈련시킵니다.
Um, and then the data set they use is, uh, 6.5 million image text pairs, uh, consisting of
음, 그리고 그들이 사용하는 데이터 세트는, 어, 650만 개의 이미지 텍스트 쌍입니다.
four million unique images.
4백만 개의 고유한 이미지.
And then here is the quantitative results.
그리고 여기에 정량적 결과가 있습니다.
Uh, note that, uh, they compare the Oscar with, uh, the previous, uh, soda models.
어, 어, 그들은 오스카상을 이전 탄산음료 모델과 비교한다는 점에 주목하세요.
Uh, the Oscar views 6.5 million, uh, uh, data set.
어, 오스카상은 650만 개의 데이터 세트를 조회합니다.
Uh, in the other part, we use over 91.
어, 다른 부분에서는 91 이상을 사용합니다.
Um, so we can see the Oscar face already outperforms the largest soda, uh, using less data set.
음, 그러면 오스카 얼굴이 더 적은 데이터 세트를 사용하여 이미 가장 큰 탄산음료보다 성능이 뛰어나다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
Um, so this, um, highlights the Oscar's parameter efficiency, uh, partially because
음, 이것은, 음, 오스카의 매개변수 효율성을 강조하는 것입니다. 부분적으로는
the use of object tags has the input point, uh, and this can use the learning of these
객체 태그를 사용하면 입력 지점이 있습니다. 어, 이는 이러한 학습을 ​​사용할 수 있습니다.
mental climates.
정신적 기후.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
So like, uh, the, the image text retrieval, I think they use cocoa, uh, cocoa, um, image
그래서, 어, 이미지 텍스트 검색과 같이 그들은 코코아, 어, 코코아, 음, 이미지를 사용하는 것 같습니다.
captioning, um, I guess that's also, um, yeah, yeah.
캡션, 음, 그것도, 음, 예, 예.
Like our 30 K and two QA.
우리의 30K와 두 개의 QA처럼 말이죠.
Yeah.
응.
They are like pretty common, uh, data sets, uh, that will be used for, uh, other following models.
그것들은 어, 다른 다음 모델에 사용될 매우 일반적인 데이터 세트와 같습니다.
Um, and then, uh, the author is further analyzed the effect of the object text.
음, 그리고, 어, 저자는 목적 텍스트의 효과를 더 분석합니다.
Uh, so as we can see for three different tasks, uh, the training using predicted tags,
어, 세 가지 다른 작업에서 볼 수 있듯이 예측 태그를 사용한 훈련은
which basically given the, uh, the region features, you want to predict what the region,
기본적으로 지역 특성을 고려하여 지역이 무엇인지 예측하고 싶고
uh, the corresponding tags are, uh, they, the, using the predicted tags, uh, takes less than
어, 해당 태그는, 어, 그들은, 예측된 태그를 사용하면, 어, 더 적은 시간이 걸립니다
half of the training time to achieve the final performance of, without using any tags.
태그를 사용하지 않고 최종 성능을 달성하는 데 훈련 시간의 절반이 소요됩니다.
This shows the efficiency of utilizing the object tags for, uh, the, and then further,
이는 객체 태그를 활용하는 효율성을 보여줍니다.
if you use the ground truth tags, it can reduce the training time by another 50%
Ground Truth 태그를 사용하면 학습 시간을 50% 더 줄일 수 있습니다.
to achieve the final performance compared with using, uh, the predicted, uh, tags.
예측된 태그를 사용하는 것과 비교하여 최종 성능을 달성하는 것입니다.
And then the, uh, qualitative results.
그리고, 음, 질적인 결과가 나옵니다.
Um, so the author visualize, uh, the text and image embeddings, uh, in a two dimensional
음, 그래서 저자는 텍스트와 이미지 임베딩을 2차원으로 시각화합니다.
visualization.
심상.
And then they find that without using any tag, we can see here, for example,
그런 다음 그들은 태그를 사용하지 않고도 여기에서 볼 수 있는 것을 발견했습니다. 예를 들어,
the image embedding per person and text embedding per person, they are pretty far away.
개인별 이미지 임베딩과 개인별 텍스트 임베딩은 꽤 거리가 멀습니다.
Versus, uh, in Oscar, they are very close.
대조적으로, 오스카에서는 그들은 매우 가깝습니다.
And same as, uh, so that's one, uh, observation, uh, so the same object between two modalities
그리고 마찬가지입니다, 어, 그게 하나의, 어, 관찰입니다, 어, 두 가지 양식 사이의 동일한 대상입니다
is quoted, right?
인용된 것 맞죠?
And then for interclass, uh, the classes of related semantics are a quarter, but this thing
그리고 인터클래스의 경우, 어, 관련 의미론 클래스는 4분의 1이지만 이건
is called, what they mean is, for example, like in this region on the right, uh, this is the
라고 불리는데, 그 의미는 예를 들어 오른쪽에 있는 이 지역과 같습니다. 어, 이것은
embeddings for all the elements.
모든 요소에 대한 임베딩.
And then we have the embeddings for example, for transportation and for the printers and
그리고 예를 들어 운송, 프린터 및
so on.
곧.
And one interesting observation was, well, first of all, kind of like,
흥미로운 관찰 중 하나는 무엇보다 먼저 다음과 같습니다.
both of these types of things can be added.
이 두 가지 유형을 모두 추가할 수 있습니다.
So I think that's kind of fun.
그래서 좀 재미있는 것 같아요.
And then the limitations about Oscar, um, so it requires a very powerful object detector
그리고 Oscar에 대한 제한 사항은 음, 매우 강력한 물체 감지기가 필요하다는 것입니다.
to handle a very complex scene.
매우 복잡한 장면을 처리하기 위해.
And it doesn't work very well when the salient objects are missing in the text.
그리고 텍스트에서 두드러진 개체가 누락되면 잘 작동하지 않습니다.
For example, this picture just has a bunch of, uh, boots, but the caption is a few good
예를 들어, 이 사진에는 부츠 한 묶음이 있지만 캡션에는 몇 가지 좋은 부츠가 있습니다.
reasons to start with controlling things.
사물을 통제하는 것부터 시작해야 하는 이유.
Hello everyone, uh, starting from here, I'm going to introduce the paper Vimbo,
안녕하세요 여러분, 어, 이제부터 Vimbo라는 논문을 소개하겠습니다.
revisiting visual representations in visual language models.
시각적 언어 모델의 시각적 표현을 다시 살펴봅니다.
And this paper is focusing on extracting better visual representation rather than just fusion
그리고 본 논문은 단순한 융합이 아닌 더 나은 시각적 표현을 추출하는 데 중점을 두고 있습니다.
the multimodal information.
다중 모드 정보.
Here's the information about the background and motivation of Vimbo.
Vimbo의 배경과 동기에 대한 정보는 다음과 같습니다.
And before that, we have to state that VLP typically consists of two stages.
그 전에 VLP는 일반적으로 두 단계로 구성된다는 점을 명시해야 합니다.
The first one is an object detection model that is pertrained to encode an image and
첫 번째는 이미지를 인코딩하도록 연동된 객체 감지 모델입니다.
the visual objects in the image to representations.
이미지의 시각적 객체를 표현으로 표현합니다.
And then we have a cross model fusion model that is pertrained to blend the text and visual
그런 다음 텍스트와 시각적 요소를 혼합하도록 훈련된 교차 모델 융합 모델이 있습니다.
representations.
표현.
In recent years, a lot of work has shown that the success of visual language portraying VLP
최근 몇 년 동안 VLP를 표현하는 시각적 언어의 성공이 많은 연구에서 나타났습니다.
in the visual language via our tasks.
우리의 작업을 통해 시각적 언어로.
For example, the via, uh, the view bird and Oscar.
예를 들어, 비아, 어, 뷰 버드와 오스카.
So we can have the architecture of object detection to the model plus the cross model
따라서 우리는 모델과 교차 모델에 대한 객체 감지 아키텍처를 가질 수 있습니다.
fusion model.
퓨전 모델.
But however, in vision language fusion model, the OD model improvement is always untouched.
그러나 비전 언어 융합 모델에서는 OD 모델 개선이 항상 그대로 유지됩니다.
And we know that the visual feature is very important in VLP tasks.
그리고 우리는 VLP 작업에서 시각적 기능이 매우 중요하다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
So actually we can leverage the large scale object attribute detection model like the
따라서 실제로 우리는 다음과 같은 대규모 객체 속성 감지 모델을 활용할 수 있습니다.
Resnext 152c4 to improve the performance of VLP tasks.
Resnext 152c4는 VLP 작업의 성능을 향상시킵니다.
And we can also use the larger dataset like visual genome VG dataset.
또한 시각적 게놈 VG 데이터 세트와 같은 더 큰 데이터 세트를 사용할 수도 있습니다.
In this part, we're going to talk about how Vimbo improves the vision in visual language.
이 부분에서는 Vimbo가 시각적 언어의 비전을 어떻게 향상시키는지에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
Just inspired by the great success of the pertrained language models, the paradigm of
학습된 언어 모델의 큰 성공에 영감을 받아
the mainstream works are actually designed in this fashion.
주류 작품은 실제로 이런 방식으로 디자인되었습니다.
Firstly, we can develop a much more diverse, richer and larger training datasets.
첫째, 훨씬 더 다양하고 풍부하며 대규모의 훈련 데이터 세트를 개발할 수 있습니다.
And then we gain new insights in object detection algorithms.
그런 다음 객체 감지 알고리즘에 대한 새로운 통찰력을 얻습니다.
And then we leverage more powerful GPUs for training bigger models.
그런 다음 더 큰 모델을 훈련하기 위해 더 강력한 GPU를 활용합니다.
However, this paper focuses on improving the object centric visual representations
그러나 본 논문에서는 객체 중심의 시각적 표현을 개선하는 데 중점을 둡니다.
from the vision side of the VLP work.
VLP 작업의 비전 측면에서.
Specifically, they developed a new object detection model.
특히 그들은 새로운 객체 감지 모델을 개발했습니다.
They can produce better visual features if images than the classic OD model.
기존 OD 모델보다 이미지가 더 나은 시각적 기능을 생성할 수 있습니다.
By enriching the visual object and attribute categories,
시각적 객체와 속성 카테고리를 풍부하게 함으로써,
enlarging the model size and training on a much larger OD dataset.
모델 크기를 확대하고 훨씬 더 큰 OD 데이터 세트에 대한 교육을 수행합니다.
Now we're going to see some little experiments and examples about how they
이제 우리는 그들이 어떻게 작동하는지에 대한 몇 가지 작은 실험과 예를 볼 것입니다.
improve the vision in visual languages.
시각적 언어로 시력을 향상시킵니다.
Before that, we want to say that actually they pertrained a large scale object attribute
그 전에 우리는 실제로 그들이 대규모 개체 속성을 가지고 있다고 말하고 싶습니다.
detection model based on the Resnext 152c4, let's call it c4 over here.
Resnext 152c4를 기반으로 한 감지 모델을 여기서는 c4라고 부르겠습니다.
And the new model is better designed for VL tasks and is bigger and trained on much
그리고 새로운 모델은 VL 작업에 더 적합하게 설계되었으며 더 크고 더 많은 교육을 받았습니다.
larger amounts of data combining multiple public object detection datasets.
여러 공공 객체 감지 데이터 세트를 결합하여 더 많은 양의 데이터를 생성합니다.
So compare with common object classes in typical OD models in the left figure,
따라서 왼쪽 그림의 일반적인 OD 모델의 일반적인 개체 클래스와 비교하면,
the rich and diverse region features from their model in the right figure
오른쪽 그림의 모델에서 풍부하고 다양한 지역의 특징을 볼 수 있습니다.
are crucial for vision language tasks.
비전 언어 작업에 중요합니다.
For concept detected by both models, for example, the boy attributes from their model often
예를 들어, 두 모델 모두에서 감지된 개념의 경우 소년은 해당 모델의 속성을 자주 사용합니다.
offer richer information like young barefoot shirtless, standing,
맨발의 맨발의 젊은, 서있는 모습,
serving, smiling, little playing, looking blonde, there are all the attributes information.
서빙, 미소, 작은 놀이, 금발처럼 보이는 등 모든 속성 정보가 있습니다.
So to improve the OD model for VL tasks, they utilize four public object detection datasets
따라서 VL 작업에 대한 OD 모델을 개선하기 위해 4개의 공용 개체 감지 데이터 세트를 활용합니다.
because most datasets do not have attribute annotations.
대부분의 데이터 세트에는 속성 주석이 없기 때문입니다.
They adopt a pre-training and fine-tuning strategy to build their OD model.
그들은 OD 모델을 구축하기 위해 사전 훈련 및 미세 조정 전략을 채택합니다.
Firstly, they pertrain an OD model on a large scale corpus consisting of the combination of
첫째, 그들은 다음의 조합으로 구성된 대규모 코퍼스에서 OD 모델을 훈련시킵니다.
four public datasets by sampling, balancing, and merging.
샘플링, 밸런싱, 병합을 통해 4개의 공개 데이터 세트를 생성합니다.
And then fine-tune the OD model on VG to inject attribute information to add an attribute branch
그런 다음 VG에서 OD 모델을 미세 조정하여 속성 정보를 주입하여 속성 분기를 추가합니다.
to the pre-trained OD model, making it capable of detecting both objects and attributes.
사전 훈련된 OD 모델에 적용하여 객체와 속성을 모두 감지할 수 있습니다.
Now we're going to revisit the VL model to reinforce our understanding.
이제 우리는 이해를 강화하기 위해 VL 모델을 다시 살펴보겠습니다.
And deep learning-based VL models typically consist of two modules,
그리고 딥러닝 기반 VL 모델은 일반적으로 두 개의 모듈로 구성됩니다.
an image understanding module vision, and a cross-modal understanding module VL.
이미지 이해 모듈 비전 및 교차 모달 이해 모듈 VL.
Here we can give some definition.
여기서 우리는 몇 가지 정의를 내릴 수 있습니다.
Vision is the image understanding module.
Vision은 이미지 이해 모듈입니다.
VL is the cross-modal understanding module.
VL은 교차 모달 이해 모듈입니다.
And IMG actually means the vision.
그리고 IMG는 실제로 비전을 의미합니다.
And Q is the semantic representation of the image, like the object tag.
그리고 Q는 객체 태그와 마찬가지로 이미지의 의미론적 표현입니다.
And V is the distribution representation of the image, like the visual representation.
그리고 V는 시각적 표현과 마찬가지로 이미지의 분포 표현입니다.
And W is the language or text, just like the question in VQA.
그리고 W는 VQA의 질문과 마찬가지로 언어 또는 텍스트입니다.
And Y could be the output or text, just like the answer to be predicted in VQA tasks.
그리고 Y는 VQA 작업에서 예측되는 답변과 마찬가지로 출력 또는 텍스트일 수 있습니다.
So the convention in VL model is just like firstly we unify vision and language modeling VL
따라서 VL 모델의 규칙은 먼저 비전과 언어 모델링 VL을 통합하는 것과 같습니다.
with transformer.
변압기와 함께.
And then we portray the unified VL with large-scale text image corpora.
그런 다음 대규모 텍스트 이미지 말뭉치로 통합 VL을 묘사합니다.
Now let's briefly talk about the dataset they use in pre-training.
이제 사전 훈련에 사용하는 데이터 세트에 대해 간략하게 이야기하겠습니다.
They build their pre-training corpus based on three types of existing vision and VL datasets.
그들은 세 가지 유형의 기존 비전 및 VL 데이터 세트를 기반으로 사전 훈련 코퍼스를 구축합니다.
Firstly, the image captioning datasets.
첫째, 이미지 캡션 데이터 세트입니다.
Secondly, the visual QA datasets, including GQA and thirdly, image tagging datasets.
두 번째는 GQA를 포함한 시각적 QA 데이터세트이고, 세 번째는 이미지 태깅 데이터세트입니다.
And there are two terms in the OSCAR plus pre-training loss, as in the equation,
OSCAR에는 방정식과 같이 사전 훈련 손실과 함께 두 개의 항이 있습니다.
which is the most important part about the paper.
논문에서 가장 중요한 부분이다.
Here, lossMTL is the masked token loss defined on the text modality for image animation,
여기서 lossMTL은 이미지 애니메이션의 텍스트 양식에 정의된 마스크된 토큰 손실입니다.
just following closely OSCAR.
OSCAR를 밀접하게 따르고 있습니다.
And then the lossCl3 is a novel three-way contrastive loss to effectively
그리고 lossCl3은 효과적으로 새로운 3방향 대비 손실입니다.
optimize training objectives used for VQA and text image matching.
VQA 및 텍스트 이미지 매칭에 사용되는 교육 목표를 최적화합니다.
Here we're going to talk about the specifics of the loss function.
여기서는 손실 함수의 구체적인 내용에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
For the lossMTL, the word tokens of the image caption is W.
lossMTL의 경우 이미지 캡션의 단어 토큰은 W입니다.
And word tokens of object text Q share the same linguistic semantic space.
그리고 목적어 Q의 단어 토큰은 동일한 언어 의미 공간을 공유합니다.
And the lossMTL is applied on tokens of both W and Q.
그리고 lossMTL은 W와 Q 토큰 모두에 적용됩니다.
So we define the discrete token sequence as H equals to W and Q.
따라서 우리는 이산 토큰 시퀀스를 H가 W 및 Q와 동일하다고 정의합니다.
And then we apply the lossMTL for pre-training.
그런 다음 사전 훈련을 위해 lossMTL을 적용합니다.
At each iteration, we can randomly mask each input token in H with a probability
각 반복에서 H의 각 입력 토큰을 확률로 무작위로 마스킹할 수 있습니다.
and replace the mask1 HI with a special token mask.
마스크1 HI를 특수 토큰 마스크로 교체합니다.
The goal of this training is to predict these masked tokens based on their surrounding tokens
이 훈련의 목표는 주변 토큰을 기반으로 마스크된 토큰을 예측하는 것입니다.
and image features by minimizing the negative likelihood,
부정적인 우도를 최소화하여 이미지 특징을 파악하고,
by minimizing the negative log likelihood, actually.
실제로 음의 로그 우도를 최소화함으로써 말이죠.
So totally the same process as BERT.
따라서 BERT와 완전히 동일한 프로세스입니다.
Now we're going to talk about the lossCl3, which takes into account two types of training samples
이제 두 가지 유형의 훈련 샘플을 고려하는 lossCl3에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
X. And we take a VQA example over here, like the question, answer,
X. 여기에 VQA 예를 들어보겠습니다. 예를 들어 질문, 답변,
and image features triplets of the VQA dataset.
이미지는 VQA 데이터세트의 삼중항을 특징으로 합니다.
To compute the contrastive losses, the negative examples need to be constructed.
대비 손실을 계산하려면 부정적인 예를 구성해야 합니다.
And we can construct the negative or unmatched triplets for training samples and the polluted
그리고 훈련 샘플과 오염된 샘플에 대해 음수 또는 일치하지 않는 삼중항을 구성할 수 있습니다.
answers. So now to classify whether a question and answer image triplet contains a polluted
답변. 이제 질문과 답변 이미지 삼중항에 오염된 이미지가 포함되어 있는지 여부를 분류해 보겠습니다.
answer is an answer selection task for VQA.
답변은 VQA의 답변 선택 작업입니다.
Since the encoding of CLS token in BERT can be viewed as a representation of the triplet W,
BERT에서 CLS 토큰의 인코딩은 삼중항 W의 표현으로 볼 수 있으므로,
Q, and V, we can apply a fully connected layer on the top of it as a three-way classifier F
Q, V, 그 위에 완전히 연결된 레이어를 3방향 분류기 F로 적용할 수 있습니다.
to predict whether the triplet is matched or contains a polluted Q.
삼중항이 일치하는지 또는 오염된 Q를 포함하는지 예측합니다.
So now we can easily build the training set by sampling from all Qs in the corpus.
이제 코퍼스의 모든 Q에서 샘플링하여 훈련 세트를 쉽게 구축할 수 있습니다.
Now the training model is trying to predict if the given triplet contains the true answer for the
이제 훈련 모델은 주어진 삼중항에 대한 참 답이 포함되어 있는지 예측하려고 합니다.
question. Here we can talk about the training models and the architecture and the parameters.
질문. 여기서는 훈련 모델과 아키텍처, 매개변수에 대해 이야기할 수 있습니다.
They portray the model initialized with BERT and to ensure that the image region features have the
BERT로 초기화된 모델을 묘사하고 이미지 영역 기능이 다음과 같은지 확인합니다.
same input embedding size in BERT, they need to transform region features using a linear projection
BERT에서 동일한 입력 임베딩 크기를 사용하려면 선형 투영을 사용하여 영역 기능을 변환해야 합니다.
via the matrix W. So the trainable parameters are theta, including BERT, theta BERT, and W parameters.
행렬 W를 통해. 따라서 훈련 가능한 매개변수는 BERT, theta BERT 및 W 매개변수를 포함한 theta입니다.
So far we already talked about how to unify text embedding and image embedding through
지금까지 우리는 이미 텍스트 임베딩과 이미지 임베딩을 통합하는 방법에 대해 이야기했습니다.
multimodal pre-training models to have a unified embedding. And now we're talking about how to
통합된 임베딩을 갖기 위한 다중 모드 사전 훈련 모델. 이제 우리는 방법에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
use the unified embedding to finish the downstream tasks. I'm taking two types of downstream tasks.
통합 임베딩을 사용하여 다운스트림 작업을 완료합니다. 저는 두 가지 유형의 다운스트림 작업을 수행하고 있습니다.
As examples, and we start with generation tasks. For example, image captioning.
예를 들어 생성 작업부터 시작합니다. 예를 들어 이미지 캡션이 있습니다.
And the captioning task is to generate a natural language caption for an image. Firstly,
그리고 캡션 작업은 이미지에 대한 자연어 캡션을 생성하는 것입니다. 첫째로,
we fine-tune the model using the sequence-to-sequence objective. So each training sample is converted
시퀀스 대 시퀀스 목표를 사용하여 모델을 미세 조정합니다. 따라서 각 훈련 샘플은 변환됩니다.
to a triplet consisting of a caption, a set of image region features, and a set of object text.
캡션, 이미지 영역 기능 집합, 개체 텍스트 집합으로 구성된 삼중항으로 구성됩니다.
And then we randomly mask out the captioned tokens and use the encoding of the remaining
그런 다음 캡션이 있는 토큰을 무작위로 마스크 처리하고 나머지 토큰의 인코딩을 사용합니다.
context to predict the mask's token in the unidirectional generation process.
단방향 생성 프로세스에서 마스크의 토큰을 예측하는 컨텍스트입니다.
So during inference, we first encode the image regions, object tags, and a special token CLS
따라서 추론 중에 먼저 이미지 영역, 객체 태그 및 특수 토큰 CLS를 인코딩합니다.
in BERT as input. Then the model starts to generate using the mask token mechanism,
BERT에서 입력으로. 그런 다음 모델은 마스크 토큰 메커니즘을 사용하여 생성을 시작합니다.
just totally like in BERT. Here we're going to talk about the VQA and GQA about the
BERT와 완전히 같습니다. 여기서는 VQA와 GQA에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
understanding tasks. VQA and GQA are two widely used understanding tasks for evaluating VL models,
작업 이해. VQA와 GQA는 VL 모델을 평가하기 위해 널리 사용되는 두 가지 이해 작업입니다.
and the tasks require the model to answer natural language questions based on an image.
그리고 작업을 수행하려면 모델이 이미지를 기반으로 자연어 질문에 대답해야 합니다.
So for each question, the model picks an answer from a shared answer set.
따라서 각 질문에 대해 모델은 공유 답변 세트에서 답변을 선택합니다.
We'll fine-tune our VQA task. We construct one input sequence, which contains the concatenation
VQA 작업을 미세 조정하겠습니다. 연결을 포함하는 하나의 입력 시퀀스를 구성합니다.
of a given question and the object text and region features, and then the CLS token output
주어진 질문과 개체 텍스트 및 지역 특징, 그리고 CLS 토큰 출력
from the model is fed to a task-specific linear classifier for prediction.
모델의 데이터는 예측을 위해 작업별 선형 분류기에 공급됩니다.
Specifically, we treat VQA as a multi-label classification problem, assigning a soft target
구체적으로 우리는 VQA를 다중 라벨 분류 문제로 취급하여 소프트 타겟을 할당합니다.
score to each answer based on its relevancy to the human answer responses, and then we
인간의 답변 응답과의 관련성을 기준으로 각 답변에 점수를 매긴 다음
fine-tune the model by minimizing the cross entropy loss computed using the predicted scores
예측 점수를 사용하여 계산된 교차 엔트로피 손실을 최소화하여 모델을 미세 조정합니다.
and the soft target scores. And at inference stage, we can just simply use a soft max function
그리고 소프트 타겟 점수. 추론 단계에서는 간단하게 Soft Max 기능을 사용할 수 있습니다.
for prediction.
예측을 위해.
This paper actually tells us how to improve performance using more sophisticated object
이 문서는 실제로 보다 정교한 객체를 사용하여 성능을 향상시키는 방법을 알려줍니다.
detection models and fine-tuning for VL tasks. However, with the rise of large language models,
VL 작업을 위한 감지 모델 및 미세 조정. 그러나 대규모 언어 모델이 등장하면서
the entire AI community, including the CV and NLP, is paying more and more attention to the
CV와 NLP를 포함한 전체 AI 커뮤니티는 점점 더 많은 관심을 기울이고 있습니다.
possibility of completing downstream tasks using only zero shot. So in the following,
제로 샷만을 사용하여 다운스트림 작업을 완료할 가능성. 그래서 다음에서,
we will introduce one of the most important milestones to open the gate to zero shot in
제로 샷의 문을 여는 가장 중요한 이정표 중 하나를 소개하겠습니다.
multi-modal models, CLIP. Starting from here, we're going to talk about the contrastive
다중 모드 모델, CLIP. 이제부터 대조에 대해 이야기해보겠습니다.
language image per training that is kind of different from the two papers that we just
우리가 방금 제시한 두 논문과는 좀 다른 훈련별 언어 이미지
talked about. For example, now let's review again the main representation learning paradigm in CV.
이야기했다. 예를 들어 이제 CV의 주요 표현 학습 패러다임을 다시 검토해 보겠습니다.
Firstly, we need to build a connection between the image and text, such as using the image and
첫째, 이미지와 텍스트를 활용하는 등 이미지와 텍스트 사이의 연결을 구축해야 합니다.
text pair data set to learn the representation from each other, just like Oscar does. Then we
오스카처럼 서로 표현을 학습하기 위한 텍스트 쌍 데이터 세트입니다. 그러면 우리는
can obtain more data for weekly supervised pre-training, but no matter how many classes
주간 지도 사전 훈련을 통해 더 많은 데이터를 얻을 수 있지만, 수업 수에 관계없이
there are, in the data set, the final classifier is actually static and limited, because we still
데이터 세트에는 최종 분류자가 실제로 정적이고 제한적입니다.
have to fix it to the certain number of classes for classification, and this definitely limits the
분류를 위해 특정 클래스 수로 고정해야 하며 이로 인해 확실히 제한됩니다.
zero shot capability of the model, just like in view. So combining these two methods, we can
보기에서와 마찬가지로 모델의 제로 샷 기능. 따라서 이 두 가지 방법을 결합하면 다음과 같은 결과를 얻을 수 있습니다.
consider obtaining a large number of pairs of text and image from the internet to expand the data,
데이터를 확장하기 위해 인터넷에서 많은 수의 텍스트와 이미지 쌍을 얻는 것을 고려하십시오.
and then we figured out a way to have representations for classification without using a static
그리고 나서 우리는 정적 변수를 사용하지 않고 분류를 위한 표현을 갖는 방법을 알아냈습니다.
classifier. And learning directly from raw text about images is a good idea, which leverages
분류자. 그리고 이미지에 대한 원시 텍스트에서 직접 학습하는 것은 좋은 생각입니다.
a much broader source of supervision.
훨씬 더 광범위한 감독 소스.
From here, we're going to see the famous paper, CLIP, Learning Transferable Visual Models
이제부터 유명한 논문인 CLIP, Learning Transferable Visual Models를 살펴보겠습니다.
from Natural Language Supervision, and this paper is focusing on introducing self-supervised
Natural Language Supervision의 논문이며, 본 논문은 자기지도 학습을 소개하는 데 중점을 두고 있습니다.
signals widely used in NLP intervention. Now we're going to see the background and motivation
NLP 개입에 널리 사용되는 신호. 이제 배경과 동기를 살펴보겠습니다.
by CLIP. A lot of recent work has shown that the success of pre-training models in NLP viewed,
CLIP으로. 최근의 많은 연구에 따르면 NLP에서 사전 훈련 모델의 성공은 다음과 같습니다.
like the GPT family, and we already see that the zero shot CV tasks had seen the improved
GPT 제품군과 마찬가지로 제로 샷 CV 작업이 개선된 것을 이미 확인했습니다.
performance in network and more targeted weak supervision. But just as I mentioned before,
네트워크 성능 및 보다 표적화된 약한 감독. 하지만 아까도 말씀드렸듯이,
actually the SOTA CV system still has some problem, for example, the fixed set of pre-determined object
실제로 SOTA CV 시스템에는 여전히 몇 가지 문제가 있습니다. 예를 들어 미리 결정된 개체의 고정 세트가 있습니다.
categories, or the low generality and usability. So CLIP is trying to design a bigger model that
카테고리 또는 낮은 일반성과 유용성. 그래서 CLIP은 더 큰 모델을 디자인하려고 합니다.
close this gap by using the big data sets and the larger model size.
빅 데이터 세트와 더 큰 모델 크기를 사용하여 이러한 격차를 해소합니다.
This paper demonstrates that the simple pre-training task of predicting which caption
이 논문은 어떤 캡션을 예측하는 간단한 사전 훈련 작업을 보여줍니다.
goes with which image is already an efficient and scalable way to learn SOTA image representations,
어떤 이미지가 이미 SOTA 이미지 표현을 학습하는 효율적이고 확장 가능한 방법인지,
and after pre-training, Natural Language is used to reference the learned visual concepts,
사전 훈련 후 Natural Language를 사용하여 학습된 시각적 개념을 참조하고,
which enable zero shot transfer of the model to downstream tasks. So CLIP can perform many types
모델을 다운스트림 작업으로 제로 샷 전송할 수 있습니다. 따라서 CLIP은 다양한 유형을 수행할 수 있습니다.
of fine-grained object classification, and the model is often competitive with a fully supervised
세밀한 객체 분류가 가능하며 모델은 종종 완전히 감독되는 모델과 경쟁적입니다.
baseline without the need for any data set specific training, just like in this figure shows.
이 그림에 표시된 것처럼 데이터 세트별 교육이 필요 없이 기준선을 따릅니다.
Here we're going to talk about the method of CLIP. And before that, we still have to clear about
여기에서는 CLIP의 방법에 대해 이야기하겠습니다. 그리고 그 전에 우리는 아직 정리해야 할 것이 있습니다
a problem. The problem is that we want to use the Natural Language supervision signals to train
문제. 문제는 우리가 자연어 감독 신호를 사용하여 훈련하고 싶다는 것입니다.
a better visual model. And if we can get a large amount of text, image pair data from the internet
더 나은 시각적 모델. 그리고 인터넷에서 대량의 텍스트, 이미지 쌍 데이터를 얻을 수 있다면
with no need to label data anymore, then we can use this data to train larger models,
더 이상 데이터에 라벨을 붙일 필요 없이 이 데이터를 사용하여 더 큰 모델을 훈련할 수 있습니다.
even if the data is noisy. So in CLIP, firstly, they constructed a new data set of 400 million
데이터에 시끄러운 경우에도 마찬가지입니다. 그래서 CLIP에서는 먼저 4억 개의 새로운 데이터 세트를 구축했습니다.
image and text pairs collected from a variety of publicly-available sources on the internet,
인터넷에서 공개적으로 이용 가능한 다양한 소스로부터 수집된 이미지와 텍스트 쌍,
and then they need to set a pre-training optimization objective. And then they build the
그런 다음 사전 훈련 최적화 목표를 설정해야 합니다. 그런 다음 그들은
entire system and they start the pre-training task. Here we discuss the details of the pre-training task,
전체 시스템을 실행하고 사전 훈련 작업을 시작합니다. 여기서는 사전 훈련 작업의 세부 사항을 논의합니다.
which is the most important part of this paper, CLIP. Actually, a lot of work jointly trained an
이 논문의 가장 중요한 부분인 CLIP입니다. 실제로 많은 업무가 공동으로 교육을 받았습니다.
image CNN and text transformer from scratch to predict the caption of an image. They try to
이미지 CNN과 텍스트 변환기를 처음부터 다시 사용하여 이미지 캡션을 예측합니다. 그들은 노력한다
predict the exact words of the text accompanying each image. And this is a very difficult task
각 이미지에 수반되는 텍스트의 정확한 단어를 예측합니다. 그리고 이것은 매우 어려운 작업입니다
actually due to the wide variety of descriptions, comments, and related texts that co-occur with
실제로는 다양한 설명, 의견 및 관련 텍스트가 함께 발생하기 때문입니다.
the images. Although this kind of generative models of images can learn the high-quality image
이미지들. 이러한 종류의 이미지 생성 모델은 고품질 이미지를 학습할 수 있지만
representation, they still require an order of magnitude more compute than the contrastive
표현을 위해서는 여전히 대조보다 훨씬 더 많은 계산이 필요합니다.
models with the same performance. So noting these findings, they explore training a system to predict
동일한 성능을 가진 모델입니다. 따라서 이러한 발견에 주목하여 예측을 위한 시스템 교육을 탐색합니다.
only which text as a whole is paired with which image instead of the exact words of the text.
텍스트의 정확한 단어 대신 전체적으로 어떤 텍스트가 어떤 이미지와 쌍을 이루는지.
And the experiments observe a further four times of efficiency improvement in the rate of zero
그리고 실험에서는 0의 비율로 효율성이 4배 더 향상되는 것을 관찰했습니다.
shall transfer to ImageNet. Now we're going to talk about the pre-training in details.
ImageNet으로 전송됩니다. 이제 사전 훈련에 대해 자세히 이야기하겠습니다.
Given the batch of n pairs, CLIP is trained to predict which of the n by n possible pairings
n 쌍의 배치가 주어지면 CLIP은 n x n 가능한 쌍 중 어느 것이 가능한지 예측하도록 훈련됩니다.
across a batch actually occurred. So to do this, CLIP learns a multimodal embedding space by jointly
일괄적으로 실제로 발생했습니다. 이를 위해 CLIP은 공동으로 다중 모드 임베딩 공간을 학습합니다.
training an image encoder and text encoder to maximize the cosine similarity of the image
이미지의 코사인 유사성을 최대화하기 위해 이미지 인코더와 텍스트 인코더를 훈련합니다.
and text embeddings of the n real pairs in the batch, while minimizing the cosine similarity
코사인 유사성을 최소화하면서 배치에 있는 n개의 실수 쌍에 대한 텍스트 임베딩
of the embeddings of the n squared minus n incorrect pairings. And then they try to optimize
n 제곱에서 n 잘못된 쌍을 뺀 임베딩의 수입니다. 그런 다음 최적화를 시도합니다.
the symmetric loss, they try to optimize the symmetric cross entropy loss over these similarity
대칭 손실, 그들은 이러한 유사성에 대한 대칭 교차 엔트로피 손실을 최적화하려고 합니다.
scores. In specifics, transformer is selected as the text encoder and ResNet or VIT can be selected
점수. 구체적으로 텍스트 인코더로 Transformer를 선택하고 ResNet 또는 VIT를 선택할 수 있습니다.
as the image encoder. For example, the step one, we extract the feature representations of each
이미지 인코더로. 예를 들어 1단계에서는 각 항목의 특징 표현을 추출합니다.
modality from two encoders. And from steps two to three, we obtain the joint multimodal embedding
두 인코더의 양식. 그리고 2~3단계에서 공동 다중 모드 임베딩을 얻습니다.
of the same dimension through linear transformation and normalization. As step four, we perform the
선형변환과 정규화를 통해 동일한 차원을 구현합니다. 4단계에서는 다음을 수행합니다.
scale pairwise cosine similarities, pairwise cosine similarities to obtain the cosine
쌍별 코사인 유사성, 쌍별 코사인 유사성을 조정하여 코사인을 얻습니다.
similarities matrix. Finally, in step five, we just calculate the symmetric contrastive loss
유사성 매트릭스. 마지막으로 5단계에서는 대칭 대비 손실을 계산합니다.
through the cross entropy loss function.
교차 엔트로피 손실 함수를 통해
We know this pseudocode is kind of confusing, so I'm writing my code over here to enunciate what
우리는 이 의사 코드가 다소 혼란스럽다는 것을 알고 있으므로 여기에 코드를 작성하여 무엇을 설명할지 설명하겠습니다.
we do using Torch. To compute the cross entropy loss, we can design two functions, the contrastive
우리는 Torch를 사용합니다. 교차 엔트로피 손실을 계산하기 위해 두 가지 함수를 설계할 수 있습니다.
loss and CLIP loss. And in the contrastive loss, we can leverage the Torch function,
손실 및 CLIP 손실. 그리고 대비 손실에서는 Torch 기능을 활용할 수 있습니다.
union function across entropy, and we can set the corresponding lodges.
엔트로피 전반에 걸쳐 결합 기능을 수행하고 해당 롯지를 설정할 수 있습니다.
And we first compute the loss i for the image encoding, and then we compute the loss t
그리고 먼저 이미지 인코딩에 대한 손실 i를 계산한 다음 손실 t를 계산합니다.
for the text embedding, and then we calculate the average of the loss i and the loss t.
텍스트 임베딩을 위해 손실 i와 손실 t의 평균을 계산합니다.
And then we can have the final loss.
그러면 우리는 최종적인 손실을 입을 수 있습니다.
Okay, after pre-training, we have a problem which is how to do the inference. Actually,
좋아요, 사전 훈련 후에 추론을 수행하는 방법에 대한 문제가 있습니다. 실제로,
in computer vision, zero-shot learning usually refers to the study of generalizing to unseen
컴퓨터 비전에서 제로샷 학습은 일반적으로 보이지 않는 것을 일반화하는 연구를 의미합니다.
object categories in image classification. So CLIP's contrastive pre-training method
이미지 분류의 객체 카테고리. 그래서 CLIP의 대조 사전 학습 방법은
actually makes zero-shot classification very easy. For example, we have an image to predict.
실제로 제로샷 분류를 매우 쉽게 만듭니다. 예를 들어 예측할 이미지가 있습니다.
First, we get its image embedding, and then we create a data set classifier from label text,
먼저 이미지 임베딩을 얻은 다음 레이블 텍스트에서 데이터 세트 분류자를 만듭니다.
and all the labels are all encoded by the text encoder to obtain the corresponding text embedding,
모든 레이블은 모두 텍스트 인코더에 의해 인코딩되어 해당 텍스트 임베딩을 얻습니다.
and then we calculate the cosine similarity respectively. And then the prediction label
그런 다음 코사인 유사성을 각각 계산합니다. 그런 다음 예측 라벨
with the highest similarity is the top one prediction label. So in this way, the classification tax
유사성이 가장 높은 것은 최상위 예측 라벨입니다. 그래서 이런 식으로 분류세를
is no longer limited to a fixed data set or a fixed number of labels.
더 이상 고정된 데이터 세트나 고정된 수의 레이블로 제한되지 않습니다.
And actually, in pre-training, usually the text data is a full sentence describing the image in
그리고 실제로 사전 훈련에서 텍스트 데이터는 일반적으로 이미지를 설명하는 전체 문장입니다.
some way, so to help bridge this distribution gap, we can use the prompt template like a photo of a
어떤 식으로든 배포 격차를 해소하기 위해 사진과 같은 프롬프트 템플릿을 사용할 수 있습니다.
label. As a good default that helps specify the text is about the content of the image,
상표. 텍스트를 지정하는 데 도움이 되는 좋은 기본값은 이미지의 내용에 관한 것이므로,
and this often improves the performance over the baseline of using only the label text,
이는 레이블 텍스트만 사용하는 기준에 비해 성능이 향상되는 경우가 많습니다.
just similar to the prompt engineering discussion around other larger language models,
다른 더 큰 언어 모델에 대한 신속한 엔지니어링 토론과 유사합니다.
and zero-shot performance can be significantly improved by customizing the prompt text to each text.
각 텍스트에 대한 프롬프트 텍스트를 사용자 정의하면 제로샷 성능이 크게 향상될 수 있습니다.
And prompt engineering helps specify the category on many fine-grained image classification data sets.
그리고 신속한 엔지니어링은 많은 세분화된 이미지 분류 데이터 세트에서 카테고리를 지정하는 데 도움이 됩니다.
For example, on a data set about animals, we can use the prompt like a photo of a label,
예를 들어, 동물에 관한 데이터 세트에서는 라벨 사진과 같은 프롬프트를 사용할 수 있습니다.
a type of pet, as prompt. So this can help provide a context very well.
프롬프트에 따라 애완동물의 일종입니다. 따라서 이는 맥락을 매우 잘 제공하는 데 도움이 될 수 있습니다.
Over here, we can look at the zero-shot classification result from Clip,
여기서는 Clip의 제로샷 분류 결과를 볼 수 있습니다.
and the performance of Clip is very strong because Clip is zero-shot without using any data from
Clip은 데이터를 전혀 사용하지 않고 제로샷을 하기 때문에 Clip의 성능은 매우 강력합니다.
downstream tasks, while linear probe ResNet 50 used the downstream data to find human waste classifier.
선형 프로브 ResNet 50은 다운스트림 데이터를 사용하여 인간 배설물 분류기를 찾았습니다.
Finally, we can conclude that although Clip's zero-shot performance is generally better than
마지막으로 Clip의 제로샷 성능은 일반적으로 Clip보다 우수하지만 결론을 내릴 수 있습니다.
supervised baseline ResNet 50, it is actually kind of weaker than SOTA methods of many downstream
감독된 기준 ResNet 50은 실제로 많은 다운스트림의 SOTA 방법보다 약합니다.
tasks, especially those fine-grained classification and abstract tasks. So the transfer learning of
작업, 특히 세분화된 분류 및 추상 작업. 그래서 전이학습은
Clip has been explored very much recent years. And secondly, although the Clip zero-shot classifier
Clip은 최근 몇 년 동안 매우 많이 연구되었습니다. 둘째, Clip 제로샷 분류기는
can work on a wide range of tasks, the essence of Clip is to compare and reason within the limited
다양한 작업을 할 수 있지만 제한된 범위 내에서 비교하고 추론하는 것이 Clip의 본질입니다.
classes and cannot generate new concepts as completely flexible as image captions,
클래스이며 이미지 캡션만큼 완전히 유연한 새로운 개념을 생성할 수 없습니다.
because Clip, like Oscar, is not a generative model either. Despite these problems,
Clip도 Oscar와 마찬가지로 생성 모델이 아니기 때문입니다. 이러한 문제에도 불구하고,
we'll say Clip is the basis for a series of excellent work in recent years,
Clip은 최근 몇 년간 일련의 훌륭한 작품의 기반이 되었다고 말할 수 있습니다.
because it provides a very good standing point for zero-shot tasks and unify text image representation.
제로샷 작업을 위한 매우 좋은 위치를 제공하고 텍스트 이미지 표현을 통합하기 때문입니다.
Very soon, we're going to see a series of new Clip-based models that can be applied to a large
조만간 우리는 대규모 애플리케이션에 적용할 수 있는 일련의 새로운 클립 기반 모델을 보게 될 것입니다.
number of VL tasks.
VL 작업 수.
In this part, we're going to introduce the famous paper Align Scaling of Visual and Visual
이번 파트에서는 ​​유명한 논문 Align Scaling of Visual and Visual을 소개하겠습니다.
Language Representation Learning with Noisy Text Supervision. And the paper is focusing on the scale
시끄러운 텍스트 감독을 통한 언어 표현 학습. 그리고 그 논문은 규모에 초점을 맞추고 있어요
of the corpus making up for noise and leading to SOTA representations.
노이즈를 보완하고 SOTA 표현으로 이어지는 코퍼스입니다.
Over here, we're going to talk about the background and motivation about Align.
여기서는 Align을 설립하게 된 배경과 동기에 대해 이야기해보겠습니다.
For visual language, the popular datasets like Clip all involve a non-trivial data collection
시각적 언어의 경우 Clip과 같은 널리 사용되는 데이터 세트에는 모두 사소한 데이터 수집이 포함됩니다.
and a cleaning process. And this costly curation process limits the size of datasets and hence
그리고 청소 과정. 그리고 비용이 많이 드는 이 큐레이션 프로세스는 데이터 세트의 크기를 제한하므로
hinders the scaling of the trained models. And in this paper, they leverage noisy datasets of
훈련된 모델의 확장을 방해합니다. 그리고 이 논문에서는 잡음이 많은 데이터 세트를 활용합니다.
over one billion image taxpayers obtained without expensive filtering or post-processing steps.
값비싼 필터링이나 후처리 단계 없이 10억 명 이상의 이미지 납세자가 획득했습니다.
So a single dual encoder architecture learns to align visual and language representations
따라서 단일 듀얼 인코더 아키텍처는 시각적 표현과 언어 표현을 정렬하는 방법을 학습합니다.
of the image and taxpayers using a contrastive loss, just same as Clip. And they show that the
Clip과 동일하게 대비 손실을 사용하여 이미지와 납세자를 계산합니다. 그리고 그들은
scale of the corpus can make up for its noise and leads to SOTA representations even with such a
코퍼스의 규모는 노이즈를 보완할 수 있으며 그러한 경우에도 SOTA 표현으로 이어질 수 있습니다.
simple learning scheme. The aligned visual and language representations enables zero-shot image
간단한 학습 계획. 정렬된 시각적 및 언어 표현을 통해 제로샷 이미지가 가능합니다.
classification. And the representations also enable cross-modality search with complex text and text
분류. 또한 표현을 통해 복잡한 텍스트와 텍스트를 사용한 교차 양식 검색도 가능합니다.
plus image queries. Here we're going to talk about the noisy image text datasets.
플러스 이미지 쿼리. 여기서는 노이즈가 있는 이미지 텍스트 데이터세트에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
Actually, the focus of their work is to scale up visual and language representation learning.
실제로 그들의 작업의 초점은 시각적 및 언어 표현 학습을 확장하는 것입니다.
So for this purpose, they resort to a large larger dataset than existing ones.
따라서 이를 위해 기존 데이터보다 더 큰 데이터 세트를 사용합니다.
In particular, we follow the methodology of constructing concept perceptions dataset to
특히, 우리는 개념 인식 데이터 세트를 구성하는 방법론을 따릅니다.
get a version of raw English image text data. And here, for the purpose of scaling,
원시 영어 이미지 텍스트 데이터 버전을 가져옵니다. 그리고 여기서는 스케일링을 목적으로
they just trade quality for scale by giving up most of the cleaning steps in the original work.
그들은 원본 작업의 대부분의 청소 단계를 포기함으로써 규모와 품질을 교환합니다.
Instead, they only apply the minimal frequency-based filtering. And obviously, this one is
대신 최소한의 주파수 기반 필터링만 적용합니다. 그리고 분명히 이것은
totally noise sample, the second sample. And other samples do have some noisy information
전체 노이즈 샘플, 두 번째 샘플. 그리고 다른 샘플에는 약간의 시끄러운 정보가 있습니다.
in the text, just like this caption above this image or this caption above this image.
이 이미지 위의 이 캡션이나 이 이미지 위의 이 캡션과 같이 텍스트에 표시됩니다.
Over here, I have to emphasize again that their work is very similar to Clip, which
여기서는 그들의 작업이 Clip과 매우 유사하다는 점을 다시 한 번 강조하고 싶습니다.
proposes visual representation learning via natural language supervision in a similar
유사한 방식으로 자연어 감독을 통한 시각적 표현 학습을 제안합니다.
contrastive learning setting. Besides, using different vision and language encoder
대조 학습 설정. 게다가, 다른 비전과 언어 인코더를 사용하여
architectures, the key difference is on training data. For example, a line follows a natural
아키텍처에서 주요 차이점은 훈련 데이터에 있습니다. 예를 들어, 선은 자연을 따릅니다.
distribution of the image text pairs from the raw data, while Clip collects the dataset by
원시 데이터에서 이미지 텍스트 쌍을 배포하는 반면 Clip은 다음을 통해 데이터세트를 수집합니다.
constructing the high-frequency visual concepts from English Wikipedia. And this work demonstrates
영어 Wikipedia에서 고주파 시각적 개념을 구성합니다. 그리고 이 작품은 보여줍니다.
that strong visual and vision language representations can be learned with a dataset that doesn't
강력한 시각적 및 시각 언어 표현은 그렇지 않은 데이터세트를 사용하여 학습할 수 있습니다.
require expert knowledge to cure it. So this is the difference between a line and Clip.
치료하려면 전문적인 지식이 필요합니다. 이것이 라인과 클립의 차이점입니다.
Over here, we're going to talk about the method of a line.
여기서는 선의 방법에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
Visual and language representations actually are joined to learn from noisy image art text data.
시끄러운 이미지 아트 텍스트 데이터로부터 학습하기 위해 시각적 표현과 언어 표현이 실제로 결합됩니다.
And the representations can be used for vision-only or vision-language task
그리고 표현은 비전 전용 또는 비전 언어 작업에 사용될 수 있습니다.
transfer. Without any fine-tuning, a line powers the zero-shot visual classification
옮기다. 미세 조정 없이 라인만으로 제로샷 시각적 분류 가능
and cross-modal search, including the image to text search, the text to image search,
이미지에서 텍스트로 검색, 텍스트에서 이미지로 검색을 포함한 교차 모드 검색,
and even search with joint image plus text curies. Right now, over here, we can see the text encoder
공동 이미지와 텍스트 큐리로 검색할 수도 있습니다. 지금 여기에서 텍스트 인코더를 볼 수 있습니다.
and the image encoder. And we just feed the noisy image text data to the encoders,
그리고 이미지 인코더. 그리고 우리는 노이즈가 있는 이미지 텍스트 데이터를 인코더에 공급하기만 하면 됩니다.
and we use the contrasted learning laws to optimize the network. So this is the portraying
그리고 우리는 대조 학습 법칙을 사용하여 네트워크를 최적화합니다. 그래서 이것이 묘사입니다
part. It's kind of easy. Specifically, they portray a line using a dual encoder architecture,
부분. 좀 쉽습니다. 구체적으로 듀얼 인코더 아키텍처를 사용하여 라인을 묘사합니다.
just I mentioned before, and the model consists of a pair of image and text encoders with a
앞서 언급했듯이 모델은 한 쌍의 이미지 인코더와 텍스트 인코더로 구성됩니다.
cosine similarity combination function at the top. And they use a vision net as the image encoder
상단의 코사인 유사성 조합 기능. 그리고 그들은 비전 넷을 이미지 인코더로 사용합니다.
and BERT with CLS token embedding as the text embedding encoder. A fully connected layer with
텍스트 임베딩 인코더로 CLS 토큰 임베딩을 사용하는 BERT. 완전히 연결된 레이어
linear activation is added on top of BERT encoder to match the dimension from the image power.
이미지 전력의 차원과 일치하도록 BERT 인코더 위에 선형 활성화가 추가됩니다.
And both image and text encoders are trained from scratch. The image and text encoders are
이미지와 텍스트 인코더는 모두 처음부터 학습됩니다. 이미지 및 텍스트 인코더는 다음과 같습니다.
optimized via normalized softmax laws. So in training the treat, matched image text pairs as
정규화된 소프트맥스 법칙을 통해 최적화되었습니다. 따라서 치료 훈련에서 일치하는 이미지 텍스트 쌍은 다음과 같습니다.
positive. And all other random image text pairs that can be formed in a training batch as negative.
긍정적인. 그리고 훈련 배치에서 음성으로 형성될 수 있는 다른 모든 임의의 이미지 텍스트 쌍입니다.
Over here, we're going to talk about the loss function about a line.
여기서는 선에 대한 손실함수에 대해 이야기해보겠습니다.
Now let's look at their optimization objective. They just try to minimize the sum of two losses,
이제 최적화 목표를 살펴보겠습니다. 그들은 단지 두 가지 손실의 합을 최소화하려고 노력할 뿐입니다.
one for image to text classification, and the other for text to image classification.
하나는 이미지-텍스트 분류용이고 다른 하나는 텍스트-이미지 분류용입니다.
And over here, the xi and yj are the normalized embedding of image in the i-th pair and that
그리고 여기에서 xi와 yj는 i번째 쌍에 있는 이미지의 정규화된 임베딩입니다.
of text in the j-th pair, respectively. And capital N is the batch size, and sigma term is the hyper
j번째 쌍의 텍스트입니다. 대문자 N은 배치 크기이고 시그마 항은 하이퍼입니다.
parameter about temperature to scale the logits. And this is very similar as what we do in CLIP.
로짓의 크기를 조정하는 온도에 대한 매개변수입니다. 이는 CLIP에서 수행하는 작업과 매우 유사합니다.
Because of the pertaining method of contrastive learning like CLIP, they naturally evaluate
CLIP과 같은 대조학습 방법이 적용되어 있기 때문에 자연스럽게 평가를 하게 됩니다.
a line models on the image to text and text to image retrieval text with and without fine-tuning
이미지의 라인 모델을 텍스트로, 텍스트를 이미지로 모델 검색 미세 조정이 있거나 없는 텍스트 검색
this point. And they also apply transfer of a line to visual classification tasks.
이 점. 또한 시각적 분류 작업에 라인 전송을 적용합니다.
And the focus of the experiment is the performance of zero shot.
그리고 실험의 초점은 제로샷의 성능이다.
Now we can look at their experiment results. The table 1 shows that compared to previous works,
이제 우리는 그들의 실험 결과를 볼 수 있습니다. 표 1은 이전 연구와 비교하여,
a line achieves SOTA results in all metrics of benchmarks. And in the zero shot setting,
라인은 벤치마크의 모든 지표에서 SOTA 결과를 달성합니다. 그리고 제로샷 설정에서는
a line gets more than 7% improvement in image retrieval tasks compared to the previous SOTA
라인은 이전 SOTA에 비해 이미지 검색 작업이 7% 이상 향상되었습니다.
CLIP. With fine-tuning, a line outperforms all existing methods by a large margin.
클립. 미세 조정을 통해 라인은 기존의 모든 방법보다 훨씬 뛰어난 성능을 발휘합니다.
And if we directly feed the text of class names into the text encoder,
그리고 클래스 이름의 텍스트를 텍스트 인코더에 직접 공급하면,
a line is able to classify images into candidate classes via image text retrieval.
라인은 이미지 텍스트 검색을 통해 이미지를 후보 클래스로 분류할 수 있습니다.
And table 2 compares the line with CLIP on ImageNet. Just similar to CLIP, a line shows the
그리고 표 2는 ImageNet의 CLIP과 라인을 비교합니다. CLIP과 유사하게 선이 표시됩니다.
great robotness on classification tasks with different image distributions. So in order to make
다양한 이미지 분포를 가진 분류 작업에 대한 뛰어난 로봇성. 그래서 만들기 위해서는
a fair camper reason, they use the same from assembly method as CLIP. Just like what we talked
공정한 캠핑 이유는 CLIP과 동일한 조립 방법을 사용하기 때문입니다. 우리가 얘기했던 것처럼
in CLIP. Each class name is expanded with a set of ROM templates defined by CLIP,
클립에서. 각 클래스 이름은 CLIP에서 정의한 ROM 템플릿 세트로 확장됩니다.
such as a photo level label.
사진 수준 라벨과 같은 것입니다.
There's also some ablation study. Actually, a large scaling training set is essential to allow
절제 연구도 있습니다. 실제로 이를 위해서는 대규모 확장 훈련 세트가 필수적입니다.
scaling up of the models and to achieve better performance. A larger model is required to fully
모델을 확장하고 더 나은 성능을 달성합니다. 완전히하려면 더 큰 모델이 필요합니다.
utilize the larger data set. And model quality improves nicely with larger backbones. Besides,
더 큰 데이터 세트를 활용하세요. 그리고 백본이 커지면 모델 품질도 크게 향상됩니다. 게다가,
as expected, scaling of image encoder capability or scaling of the image encoder capacity
예상대로 이미지 인코더 기능 확장 또는 이미지 인코더 용량 확장
is more important for vision tasks. In image text retrieval tasks, the image and text encoder
비전 작업에 더 중요합니다. 이미지 텍스트 검색 작업에서 이미지 및 텍스트 인코더는
capacities are equally important as shown in this table.
이 표에 표시된 것처럼 용량도 똑같이 중요합니다.
This part, we're going to talk about the analysis of the learned embeddings in a line model. I
이 부분에서는 라인 모델에서 학습된 임베딩 분석에 대해 이야기하겠습니다. 나
personally think the most important experiment about this paper is this part. This part is about
개인적으로 이 논문에서 가장 중요한 실험은 바로 이 부분이라고 생각합니다. 이 부분은 대략
the analysis of learned embeddings by building a simple image retrieval system to study the
간단한 이미지 검색 시스템을 구축하여 학습된 임베딩을 분석하여
behaviors of embeddings trained by a line. And the figure shows that a line can retrieve
라인에 의해 훈련된 임베딩의 동작. 그리고 그림은 라인이 검색할 수 있음을 보여줍니다.
precise images, even detailed descriptions of a scene, or fine-grained or instance-level concepts.
정확한 이미지, 장면에 대한 자세한 설명, 세부적인 또는 인스턴스 수준 개념까지.
And these examples demonstrate that the align model really can align the images and text with
그리고 이러한 예는 정렬 모델이 실제로 이미지와 텍스트를 정렬할 수 있음을 보여줍니다.
similar semantics, and that a line can generalize to noble complex concepts.
의미론이 유사하며 선이 고귀한 복잡한 개념으로 일반화될 수 있습니다.
And this is a more important experiment, I think. Previously,
그리고 이것은 더 중요한 실험이라고 생각합니다. 이전에,
word-to-vax shows that the linear relationships between word vectors emerge as a result of
word-to-vax는 단어 벡터 사이의 선형 관계가 다음의 결과로 나타난다는 것을 보여줍니다.
training them to predict adjacent words, incentives, and paragraphs. And they show that
인접한 단어, 인센티브 및 단락을 예측하도록 훈련합니다. 그리고 그들은 그것을 보여줍니다
linear relationship between image and text embeddings also emerge in a line. And we perform
이미지와 텍스트 임베딩 간의 선형 관계도 선으로 나타납니다. 그리고 우리는 공연한다
image retrieval using a combined image plus text query. Specifically, given a query image and text
이미지와 텍스트를 결합한 쿼리를 사용하여 이미지 검색. 구체적으로, 쿼리 이미지와 텍스트가 주어지면
string, we add their aligned embeddings together and use it to retrieve the relevant images.
문자열을 사용하여 정렬된 임베딩을 함께 추가하고 이를 사용하여 관련 이미지를 검색합니다.
And the figure shows the results from a variety of image plus text queries.
그리고 그림은 다양한 이미지와 텍스트 쿼리의 결과를 보여줍니다.
Those examples not only demonstrate the great
이러한 예는 위대함을 보여줄 뿐만 아니라
compositionality of aligned embeddings across vision and language domains, but also show the
비전과 언어 영역 전반에 걸쳐 정렬된 임베딩의 구성성을 보여줍니다.
feasibility of a new paradigm of search with multimodal query that would otherwise be very
그렇지 않으면 매우 어려울 수 있는 다중 모드 쿼리를 사용한 새로운 검색 패러다임의 실현 가능성
hard using only text query or image query. For example, we could turn a pair of black shoes
텍스트 쿼리나 이미지 쿼리만 사용하는 것은 어렵습니다. 예를 들어, 검은색 신발 한 켤레를 바꿀 수 있습니다.
into the identically-looking shoes with a color of red. Finally, as showing the last three rows of
똑같이 생긴 레드 컬러의 신발 속으로. 마지막으로 마지막 세 행을 보여주듯이
the figure, removing objects attributes from a scene is also possible by performing subtraction
그림에서 빼기를 수행하여 장면에서 객체 속성을 제거하는 것도 가능합니다.
in the embedding space. So far, we may have discovered how well we can unify text and
임베딩 공간에서. 지금까지 우리는 텍스트와 텍스트를 얼마나 잘 통합할 수 있는지 발견했을 것입니다.
image, we can unify text and image representations through the contrastive learning, which may be
이미지의 경우 대조 학습을 통해 텍스트와 이미지 표현을 통합할 수 있습니다.
why stable diffusion uses clip as the text and image encoder for conditional generation.
안정적인 확산이 조건부 생성을 위한 텍스트 및 이미지 인코더로 클립을 사용하는 이유.
And however, similar as clip and oscar, although align zero shot achieves very good performance,
그러나 클립 및 오스카와 유사하지만 Align Zero Shot이 매우 좋은 성능을 달성하지만,
it still cannot generate anything new or generate new concepts as completely flexible
완전히 유연하기 때문에 여전히 새로운 것을 생성하거나 새로운 개념을 생성할 수 없습니다.
acts image captions because they're not generated models. And in the following,
생성된 모델이 아니기 때문에 이미지 캡션을 수행합니다. 그리고 다음에서는
we're going to have a look at what we can do with models with the decoders.
우리는 디코더를 사용하여 모델로 무엇을 할 수 있는지 살펴보겠습니다.
All right. So quickly recap what we covered. So oscar and middle there are like single encoder
괜찮은. 우리가 다룬 내용을 빠르게 요약해 보세요. 그래서 오스카와 미들에는 단일 인코더와 같습니다.
based models, clip and align there are like dual encoder based models. Now we're going to
기반 모델, 클립 및 정렬은 듀얼 인코더 기반 모델과 같습니다. 이제 우리는
introduce some generative language image training with the decoder block from the transformer.
변환기의 디코더 블록을 사용하여 생성적 언어 이미지 훈련을 도입합니다.
So the first paper I'm going to cover is blip, bootstrapping language image per training for
그래서 제가 다룰 첫 번째 논문은 훈련당 언어 이미지를 부트스트래핑하는 blip입니다.
unified vision language understanding and generation. The main contribution is to improve
통합 비전 언어 이해 및 생성. 주요 기여는 개선이다.
the text quality by bootstrapping the contrastive training and also unify
대조 훈련을 부트스트래핑하여 텍스트 품질을 향상하고 통합
the vision language per training. So again, the background blip wants to improve the clip
훈련당 비전 언어. 다시 한 번 말씀드리지만, 배경 블립은 클립을 개선하기를 원합니다.
and the line from two perspectives. One from the model perspective, like I said,
그리고 두 가지 관점에서 본 선. 제가 말했듯이, 모델 관점에서 보면,
clip online, they adopt encoder based models. The problem with that is they are not easily
온라인으로 클립하면 인코더 기반 모델을 채택합니다. 문제는 그게 쉽지 않다는 거다.
transferred directly to text generation tasks, for example, image captioning. And then the encoder
이미지 캡션과 같은 텍스트 생성 작업으로 직접 전송됩니다. 그리고 인코더
decoder based models have not been successfully adopted for image text retrieval tasks.
디코더 기반 모델은 이미지 텍스트 검색 작업에 성공적으로 채택되지 않았습니다.
The second perspective is from the data perspective. The number of high quality human
두 번째 관점은 데이터 관점이다. 고품질 인간의 수
adornated image and text pairs, for example, MS Coco, is not enough for a large multi-model
예를 들어 MS Coco와 같은 장식된 이미지와 텍스트 쌍은 대규모 다중 모델에 충분하지 않습니다.
model training. Clip and align are portrayed on a very large but noisy web text. This can only
모델 훈련. 자르기 및 정렬은 매우 크지만 시끄러운 웹 텍스트에 표시됩니다. 이것은 단지
yield suboptimal results. And here is just a joke about an image, which is, you know, just two
최적이 아닌 결과를 얻습니다. 그리고 여기 이미지에 대한 농담이 있습니다.
leaves on a tree. The caption is congratulations, you are now the branch manager. You know, it's not
나무에 나뭇잎. 축하합니다. 이제 지점장님이 되셨습니다. 아시다시피 그렇지 않아요
a good training data to train over multi-model large units. So then the blip wants to improve
다중 모델 대형 단위를 훈련하기 위한 좋은 훈련 데이터입니다. 그럼 그 블립은 개선을 원해요
the caption quality. To solve the text quality issue, a natural approach for us is to build a
자막 품질. 텍스트 품질 문제를 해결하기 위한 자연스러운 접근 방식은
discriminator that can distinguish between a good and bad image text pairs. And a generator to
좋은 이미지 텍스트 쌍과 나쁜 이미지 텍스트 쌍을 구별할 수 있는 판별기입니다. 그리고 발전기는
synthesize better quality captions to replace the noisy captions. And then same as clip and align,
시끄러운 캡션을 대체하기 위해 더 나은 품질의 캡션을 합성합니다. 그런 다음 클립 및 정렬과 동일하게
we want to learn a uni-model encoder to align vision and language representations.
우리는 비전과 언어 표현을 정렬하기 위해 단일 모델 인코더를 배우고 싶습니다.
So here is another example to demonstrate the idea. We have an image, which has a very noisy text,
그래서 여기에 아이디어를 보여주는 또 다른 예가 있습니다. 매우 시끄러운 텍스트가 포함된 이미지가 있습니다.
blue sky bakery in the sunset park. We want to use a filter to tell this is not a correct caption.
선셋파크에 있는 블루스카이 베이커리. 우리는 필터를 사용하여 이것이 올바른 캡션이 아님을 알리고 싶습니다.
And we want to use a captioner to generate a better caption,
그리고 우리는 더 나은 캡션을 생성하기 위해 캡션 작성자를 사용하고 싶습니다.
chocolate cake with cream frosting and chocolate sprinkles on top. And then we hope that the future
그 위에 크림 프로스팅과 초콜릿 스프링클을 얹은 초콜릿 케이크. 그리고 우리는 미래를 희망합니다
can tell this is a better caption. So very simple idea. So similar as before, we want to learn
이것이 더 나은 캡션이라고 말할 수 있습니다. 매우 간단한 아이디어입니다. 예전과 너무 비슷해서 배우고 싶어
the uni-model encoder we'll start from here. So the multi-model alignment task wants to encourage
여기서부터 단일 모델 인코더를 시작하겠습니다. 따라서 다중 모델 정렬 작업은 다음을 장려하고 싶습니다.
the matched image text pairs to have similar representations in contrast to the negative
일치하는 이미지 텍스트 쌍은 네거티브와 대조적으로 유사한 표현을 갖습니다.
pairs. So same as clip. And they use the same ITC loss function as in clip. This is the company,
한 쌍. 클립과 동일합니다. 그리고 클립과 동일한 ITC 손실 함수를 사용합니다. 이 회사는,
the sum of two infoNCE losses. NCE stands for noise contrast divestimation for image detects
두 개의 infoNCE 손실의 합입니다. NCE는 이미지 감지를 위한 노이즈 대비 분할(Noise Contrast divestimation)을 나타냅니다.
and text image. And the similarity function they use in the infoNCE is the cosine similarity.
그리고 텍스트 이미지. 그리고 infoNCE에서 사용하는 유사성 함수는 코사인 유사성입니다.
And then the model structure is just the image encoder and text encoder. This is the same as
그리고 모델 구조는 단지 이미지 인코더와 텍스트 인코더입니다. 이는 다음과 같습니다.
was covered before. And then for the discriminator or the filter, we want to train a binary
이전에 다뤄졌습니다. 그런 다음 판별자나 필터의 경우 바이너리를 훈련하고 싶습니다.
classification task to predict whether an image text pair is matched or not, given the multi-model
다중 모델이 주어지면 이미지 텍스트 쌍이 일치하는지 여부를 예측하는 분류 작업
features. So here we have the same image encoder. We have the image of any features.
특징. 여기에 동일한 이미지 인코더가 있습니다. 우리는 모든 기능의 이미지를 가지고 있습니다.
And then we have an image from the text encoder. We append the encode special token at the beginning
그런 다음 텍스트 인코더의 이미지가 있습니다. 처음에 인코딩 특수 토큰을 추가합니다.
of the caption. We pass it through the cell by directional substitution. And then we feed the
캡션의. 방향 치환을 통해 셀을 통해 전달합니다. 그리고 우리는
signal from the image into the cross attention. And then at the end we have a binary classification
이미지의 신호를 교차 주의로 보냅니다. 그리고 마지막에는 이진 분류가 있습니다.
loss. And they call it ITM loss. It stands for image text matching loss. And the authors adopt a
손실. 그리고 그들은 그것을 ITM 손실이라고 부릅니다. 이는 이미지 텍스트 일치 손실을 나타냅니다. 그리고 저자는 다음을 채택합니다.
what's called hard negative sampling strategy. This is a very simple idea. We want to use negative
하드 네거티브 샘플링 전략이라고 불리는 것입니다. 이것은 매우 간단한 아이디어입니다. 우리는 부정적인 것을 사용하고 싶습니다
pairs with a higher contrast similarity from the ITC loss which we learned before.
이전에 배운 ITC 손실보다 더 높은 대비 유사성과 쌍을 이룹니다.
So we want to use more similar like image caption pairs to train our ITM loss because
따라서 우리는 ITM 손실을 훈련하기 위해 이미지 캡션 쌍과 더 유사한 것을 사용하고 싶습니다.
this is more challenging. If we use very different image and caption, it's not very
이것은 더 어렵습니다. 매우 다른 이미지와 캡션을 사용하면 그다지 좋지 않습니다.
challenging for our model to learn any informative learnings. So yeah, that's the ITM loss for the
우리 모델이 유익한 학습을 ​​학습하는 것은 어렵습니다. 네, 그게 ITM 손실입니다.
filter. And then for generator or the captioner, it's a generic task. This is new. The task is to
필터. 그리고 생성자나 캡션 작성자에게는 일반적인 작업입니다. 이것은 새로운 것입니다. 과제는
produce textual descriptions in an ultra regressive manner given an image. And in the model
이미지가 주어지면 극도로 퇴행적인 방식으로 텍스트 설명을 생성합니다. 그리고 모델에서는
architecture, this is what they call an image from the text decoder. So they swap the bi-directional
아키텍처에서는 이것이 텍스트 디코더의 이미지라고 부르는 것입니다. 그래서 그들은 양방향을 교환합니다
self-admission with a call to mask self-admission. The rest is the same. And then the output is a
마스크 자가 입장을 요청하는 자가 입장. 나머지는 동일합니다. 그러면 출력은 다음과 같습니다.
language model loss like in GPD. And then to put three loss together, we now have our blip
GPD와 같은 언어 모델 손실. 그리고 세 번의 손실을 합치면 이제 실수가 발생합니다.
architecture. So for the vision encoder, they use a VIT. The text encoder, they use a BERT. And then
건축학. 따라서 비전 인코더의 경우 VIT를 사용합니다. 텍스트 인코더는 BERT를 사용합니다. 그런 다음
they just modify the BERT transformer block to add the cross-admission. And then you get the image
교차 승인을 추가하기 위해 BERT 변환기 블록을 수정합니다. 그러면 이미지가 나타납니다.
from the text encoder. And then you change the call to, you change the bi-directional self-admission
텍스트 인코더에서. 그런 다음 통화를 양방향 자체 승인으로 변경합니다.
You got the decoder.
디코더를 얻었습니다.
Yeah, ITC is the image tax contrastive loss. That's the same as CLP. And then ITM is the image tax
네, ITC는 이미지세 대비손실입니다. CLP도 마찬가지다. 그리고 ITM은 이미지세입니다.
matching loss. This is the bi-directional classification. Basically, given the image and the
일치 손실. 이것이 양방향 분류입니다. 기본적으로 이미지와
caption, you want to know if they are a pair or not. And the data they use to train this is
캡션, 그들이 쌍인지 아닌지 알고 싶습니다. 그리고 그들이 이것을 훈련시키는 데 사용하는 데이터는 다음과 같습니다.
actually not perpetuity to get a pair of image and text. They use the ITC loss to make a new
실제로 한 쌍의 이미지와 텍스트를 얻는 것은 영구적이지 않습니다. 그들은 ITC 손실을 사용하여 새로운 것을 만듭니다.
formative sampling, which means given the text, you want to get a noisy caption, which is not the
형성 샘플링(formative sampling)은 텍스트가 주어졌을 때 시끄러운 캡션을 얻고자 함을 의미합니다.
pair, but it's very similar, symmetrical. So then this will be meaningful. Otherwise, you won't learn
쌍이지만 매우 유사하고 대칭적입니다. 그렇다면 이것은 의미가 있을 것입니다. 그렇지 않으면 배우지 못할 것이다
Yeah. And then the lovely moment loss is the generic loss.
응. 그리고 사랑스러운 순간의 손실은 일반적인 손실입니다.
And then now we have the blip that has a filter and a captioner. We can bootstrap our dataset.
이제 필터와 캡션 작성자가 있는 글이 생겼습니다. 데이터 세트를 부트스트랩할 수 있습니다.
So we start with portraying an encoder and decoder with the noisy web scale dataset.
따라서 우리는 시끄러운 웹 규모 데이터 세트를 사용하여 인코더와 디코더를 묘사하는 것부터 시작합니다.
So you have this can be very, very large. You have the image from the web and text from the web.
그래서 이것은 매우 클 수 있습니다. 웹의 이미지와 웹의 텍스트가 있습니다.
You portray our filter captioner and the UV model encoder. And then after that, you use a clean
필터 캡션 작성자와 UV 모델 인코더를 설명하셨습니다. 그런 다음 깨끗한 것을 사용하십시오.
dataset. For example, Ms. Coco, this is annotated by human. You use a smaller but good quality
데이터세트. 예를 들어 Ms. Coco는 사람이 주석을 달았습니다. 작지만 좋은 품질을 사용합니다.
dataset to fine-tune our filter and captioner. And then you use a fine-tune model to generate
필터와 캡션 작성자를 미세 조정하기 위한 데이터 세트입니다. 그런 다음 미세 조정 모델을 사용하여
systemic caption for the web dataset. So now we only feed the image to the captioner and we get
웹 데이터세트에 대한 체계적 캡션입니다. 이제 우리는 캡션 작성자에게만 이미지를 제공하고
synthesized text. And to evaluate the synthesized text and the web-based text,
합성된 텍스트. 그리고 합성된 텍스트와 웹 기반 텍스트를 평가하기 위해,
we pass both of them through the future. And we have good quality web and text pairs.
우리는 둘 다 미래를 통해 전달합니다. 그리고 우리는 좋은 품질의 웹과 텍스트 쌍을 가지고 있습니다.
And then now they use a high quality image text pairs, roughly 129 million,
그리고 이제 그들은 대략 1억 2천 9백만 개의 고품질 이미지 텍스트 쌍을 사용합니다.
which is larger and cleaner. They use this to portray a new model for a filter captioner
더 크고 깨끗합니다. 그들은 이것을 필터 캡션 작성자의 새로운 모델을 묘사하는 데 사용합니다.
and the new model encoder. And the authors find that if we don't portray a new model,
그리고 새로운 모델 인코더. 그리고 저자는 우리가 새로운 모델을 묘사하지 않으면
if we simply continue training the three models, it doesn't help. This observation
단순히 세 가지 모델을 계속해서 훈련한다면 도움이 되지 않습니다. 이 관찰
agrees with a common practice in knowledge distillation, where the student model cannot
학생 모델이 할 수 없는 지식 증류의 일반적인 관행에 동의합니다.
be initialized from the teacher model. Yes. I think the idea definitely borrows from GAN.
교사 모델에서 초기화됩니다. 예. 나는 그 아이디어가 확실히 GAN에서 빌린 것이라고 생각한다.
But I don't think they are trained together. So they use this to portray the filter and captioner.
그러나 나는 그들이 함께 훈련을 받았다고 생각하지 않습니다. 그래서 그들은 이것을 필터와 캡션 작성자를 묘사하는 데 사용합니다.
Well, I mean, if you look at the architecture, they are trained together, but they are not against
뭐, 아키텍처를 보면 같이 훈련을 하긴 하지만 반대는 안 하더군요.
each other. So they do not modify each other. No.
서로. 그래서 그들은 서로를 수정하지 않습니다. 아니요.
But I think the idea is very similar to GAN. Sorry. Go back to the previous slide.
하지만 내 생각엔 그 아이디어가 GAN과 매우 유사하다고 생각한다. 죄송합니다. 이전 슬라이드로 돌아갑니다.
The contrasted loss RTC. Should we explain again what is all over here? Do we have anything to
대조 손실 RTC. 여기에 무엇이 있는지 다시 설명해야 할까요? 우리 할 일이라도 있어?
Yeah. So that's very, it's basically the same as CLIP. You have the batch of image
응. 그러니까 기본적으로는 CLIP과 똑같습니다. 이미지 배치가 있습니다.
embeddings, like for every image in your batch. And you have the text embeddings for every caption
배치의 모든 이미지에 대한 임베딩. 그리고 모든 캡션에 대한 텍스트 임베딩이 있습니다.
in your batch. And basically you want to align the diagonal to be the highest score,
귀하의 배치에. 그리고 기본적으로 대각선을 가장 높은 점수가 되도록 정렬하려고 합니다.
because the diagonal represents the correct pairs. And the off diagonals are
대각선이 올바른 쌍을 나타내기 때문입니다. 그리고 바깥쪽 대각선은
not the same pair. They're like polluted pairs. You want to use that as a weak signal to a supervisor
같은 쌍이 아닙니다. 그들은 오염된 쌍과 같습니다. 당신은 그것을 감독자에게 보내는 약한 신호로 사용하고 싶습니다.
model to learn the same pairs. The similar semantics should be the same pair. The different
동일한 쌍을 학습하는 모델입니다. 유사한 의미는 동일한 쌍이어야 합니다. 다른
semantics should be different pairs. Yeah. So if we go back to CLIP,
의미론은 서로 다른 쌍이어야 합니다. 응. 다시 CLIP으로 돌아가면
like here. So each I is an image embedding in a batch. Each T is a text embedding in a batch.
여기처럼. 따라서 각각의 I는 배치에 포함된 이미지입니다. 각 T는 배치에 포함된 텍스트입니다.
We want to highlight the diagonals, so that if you use softmax,
우리는 대각선을 강조하고 싶기 때문에 소프트맥스를 사용하면
vertically or horizontally, the diagonal is the largest value, because they are from the same
수직 또는 수평으로 대각선이 가장 큰 값입니다. 왜냐하면 두 값은 동일하기 때문입니다.
package. Yes. I had a question just as far as the discriminator goes, right? So since we're using
패키지. 예. 판별자가 가는 한 질문이 있었습니다. 그렇죠? 그래서 우리가 사용하고 있기 때문에
this binary modifier and how about what's good, what's bad, you have to introduce some relabeling
이 이진 수정자는 무엇이 좋고 무엇이 나쁜가요? 라벨을 다시 지정해야 합니다.
on data, whereas CLIP and aligned didn't have that, right? In these situations, what we have to go
데이터에 대해서는 CLIP과 alignment에는 그런 것이 없었습니다. 그렇죠? 이런 상황에서 우리가 가야 할 일은
ahead and say, is this a good caption or is this a bad caption, right? Yeah. How many data samples
미리 말해 보세요. 이게 좋은 캡션인가요, 아니면 나쁜 캡션인가요? 응. 데이터 샘플 수
do you need to then train that discriminator? Because it would not make sense to go through
그런 다음 해당 판별자를 훈련해야 합니까? 통과하는 것은 의미가 없기 때문에
and label every single image that you describe. Yeah. So they use a noisy data set to train
설명하는 모든 단일 이미지에 라벨을 붙입니다. 응. 그래서 그들은 훈련을 위해 시끄러운 데이터 세트를 사용합니다.
the binary header. And then they use MS-Coco to fine tune them. So in their work, I don't think they
바이너리 헤더. 그런 다음 MS-Coco를 사용하여 미세 조정합니다. 그래서 그들의 일에서 나는 그들이
manually label any data set. They just use MS-Coco, which is human animated data set.
데이터 세트에 수동으로 레이블을 지정합니다. 그들은 단지 인간 애니메이션 데이터 세트인 MS-Coco를 사용합니다.
Pre-train with the noisy data set. Yeah, it's very large. They just use fine-tuning to up-sample
시끄러운 데이터 세트로 사전 훈련합니다. 응, 정말 크구나. 그들은 업샘플링을 위해 미세 조정을 사용합니다.
the clean data so that it fits more to that than the noisy stuff. Yeah. And then they use the captioner
시끄러운 것보다 데이터에 더 잘 맞도록 깨끗한 ​​데이터를 사용합니다. 응. 그런 다음 캡션 작성자를 사용합니다.
to generate synthetic text for a large-scale images. Okay. So there's no manual labeling,
대규모 이미지에 대한 합성 텍스트를 생성합니다. 좋아요. 그래서 수동으로 라벨을 붙일 필요가 없습니다.
what's good with that? You just show it. Oh, and then you show it. Just go to after. Yeah. Yeah.
그게 뭐가 좋은데? 보여주시면 됩니다. 아, 그러면 그걸 보여주죠. 그냥 다음에 가세요. 응. 응.
They introduce a signal via MS-Coco data set. Right. And the discriminator, the Cocoa one's
MS-Coco 데이터 세트를 통해 신호를 도입합니다. 오른쪽. 그리고 판별자, 코코아 하나는
good quality. Yeah. I guess it's signed into the score. And then the, how does it with a bad quality
양질. 응. 악보에 기록된 것 같아요. 그리고 품질이 좋지 않은데 어떻게 하나요?
looks like to discriminate against? I think they only use the, they only like use the good ones
차별하는 것 같나요? 내 생각에 그들은 좋은 것만 사용하는 것 같아요.
to fine-tune them. I don't think they mentioned they use a bad quality ones to fine-tune to
미세 조정합니다. 나는 그들이 품질이 좋지 않은 것을 사용하여 미세 조정한다고 언급하지 않았다고 생각합니다.
feature a captioner. Is that they're using the hard negatives from the contrastive loss
캡션 작성자가 있습니다. 그들은 대조 손실의 하드 네거티브를 사용하고 있습니까?
as negative examples for the free training? Yeah. That's in the pre-training part. But that's not,
무료 교육에 대한 부정적인 예로? 응. 사전 훈련 부분입니다. 하지만 그건 아니다.
well, yes. It's also in the fine-tune part because like in MS-Coco, each pair is like a good quality
글쎄요. MS-코코처럼 하나하나가 퀄리티가 좋기 때문에 세세하게 조정하는 부분도 있어요
pair. But if you swap the text with a different image text, it's a negative sample.
쌍. 하지만 텍스트를 다른 이미지 텍스트로 바꾸면 부정적인 샘플이 됩니다.
Okay. And then here, just a quick visualization about the performance of captioner and filter.
좋아요. 그리고 여기에서는 캡션 작성자와 필터의 성능에 대한 간단한 시각화를 제공합니다.
So these are like web-scaled, like the images from the web. The first two, the text are wrong.
따라서 이것은 웹의 이미지와 같이 웹 크기로 조정된 것과 같습니다. 처음 두 개는 텍스트가 잘못되었습니다.
And then the captioner can generate pretty decent text, which are like better than
그러면 캡션 작성자는 꽤 괜찮은 텍스트를 생성할 수 있습니다.
the text from web. And then for the third one, the web text is actually better. It knows it's a
웹에서 온 텍스트. 그리고 세 번째로는 웹 텍스트가 실제로 더 좋습니다. 그것은 다음과 같은 것을 알고 있습니다.
Cusco from like 80, but the synthetic text, it's just large-breeding with a lot of news,
80년대의 쿠스코지만 합성 텍스트는 뉴스가 많은 대규모 집단일 뿐이죠.
which is not very informative. That's from a captioner perspective. But the filter can
그다지 유익하지 않습니다. 캡션 작성자의 관점에서 본 것입니다. 하지만 필터는
identify that the text from web is better. So these three figures show the effect of
웹의 텍스트가 더 낫다는 것을 확인하십시오. 따라서 이 세 수치는 다음의 효과를 보여줍니다.
captioner and filter. And then to adopt GLEP for downstream tasks, here's just a quick
캡션 작성자 및 필터. 그런 다음 다운스트림 작업에 GLEP를 채택하려면 다음 단계를 따르세요.
visualization. For example, for VQA, we feed the image through image encoder. We have the image
심상. 예를 들어 VQA의 경우 이미지 인코더를 통해 이미지를 공급합니다. 우리는 이미지를 가지고 있습니다
embedding. And then we feed this to the text encoder with an encode token. And then we feed the output
임베딩. 그런 다음 이를 인코딩 토큰과 함께 텍스트 인코더에 제공합니다. 그런 다음 출력을 공급합니다.
to our decoder, which then can generate an open-ended VQA. And then for NLVR, this
디코더에 연결하면 개방형 VQA를 생성할 수 있습니다. 그리고 NLVR의 경우
embed for NLVR is a pair of images. Both of them pass through the image encoder. And then we have
NLVR용 삽입은 한 쌍의 이미지입니다. 둘 다 이미지 인코더를 통과합니다. 그리고 우리는
a text. And then the text will go through, will join the image encoder through the cross-encoder.
텍스트. 그런 다음 텍스트가 통과하고 크로스 인코더를 통해 이미지 인코더에 연결됩니다.
And then at the end, you need to do a binary classification problem. I won't go through
그리고 마지막에는 이진 분류 문제를 풀어야 합니다. 나는 통과하지 않을 것이다
them in detail. And then the quantitative results. So here in this table is a comparison between
자세히. 그리고 정량적 결과. 그래서 여기 이 표에는
using a captioner only and using a filter only highlighted in these three rows. So this one
캡션 작성자만 사용하고 이 세 행에서 강조 표시된 필터만 사용합니다. 그래서 이건
is a filter only. This one is the captioner only. And our observation is captioner generates
필터일 뿐입니다. 이 사람은 캡션 작성자일 뿐입니다. 그리고 우리의 관찰은 캡션 작성자가 생성한 것입니다.
more diverse captions, which contains more new information that the model could benefit from.
모델이 활용할 수 있는 더 많은 새로운 정보가 포함된 더욱 다양한 캡션입니다.
So if you use captioner only, you actually have a slightly better performance than just using the
따라서 캡션 작성자만 사용하면 실제로 캡션 작성자만 사용하는 것보다 약간 더 나은 성능을 얻을 수 있습니다.
filter only. And then for these two rows, they are using both captioner and filter. One is with
필터만. 그런 다음 이 두 행에 대해 캡션 작성자와 필터를 모두 사용하고 있습니다. 하나는 함께
a base size. The other one is a barge size. We can see that scaling up the caption and filter
기본 크기. 다른 하나는 바지선 크기입니다. 캡션과 필터의 크기가 확대되는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
from base to large. And then you remain the same size for the VIT for the vision encoder.
베이스부터 대형까지. 그런 다음 비전 인코더에 대한 VIT의 크기는 동일하게 유지됩니다.
It only improves the generative task performance. So that's the caption applied to and captioned
생성 작업 성능만 향상됩니다. 이것이 캡션이 적용되고 캡션이 붙은 것입니다.
during the shot. The image size retrievals are actually, you don't get a very good boost.
촬영 중. 이미지 크기 검색은 실제로 그다지 좋은 향상을 얻지 못합니다.
Improvement of retrieval tasks is achieved further by scaling up the vision backbone. So you
비전 백본을 확장하면 검색 작업이 더욱 향상됩니다. 그래서 당신은
need to scale up VIT on base to large. Now you combine the large caption filter, you can improve
기본적으로 VIT를 대규모로 확장해야 합니다. 이제 큰 캡션 필터를 결합하여 개선할 수 있습니다.
your story. And then they compare BLIP with Align or LBAP. The smallest BLIP, this one,
너의 이야기. 그런 다음 BLIP를 Align 또는 LBAP와 비교합니다. 가장 작은 BLIP, 이것이다.
can all perform Align, despite using less than 1% of the data. Because BLIP use 129,
1% 미만의 데이터를 사용하더라도 모두 정렬을 수행할 수 있습니다. BLIP은 129를 사용하기 때문에
Align use 14 million, and this is 1.8 billion. And the smallest BLIP also all performs LBAP,
Align은 1400만개를 사용하는데, 이는 18억개입니다. 그리고 가장 작은 BLIP도 모두 LBAP를 수행합니다.
which uses the same 14 million images as BLIP. But LBAP adopts an encoder-based only design,
BLIP과 동일한 1,400만 개의 이미지를 사용합니다. 하지만 LBAP는 인코더 기반 전용 설계를 채택하고 있어,
and it doesn't have a bootstrapping dataset. And then the next paper, sorry, any question about BLIP?
부트스트래핑 데이터 세트가 없습니다. 그리고 다음 논문은 죄송합니다. BLIP에 관해 질문 있으신가요?
So far so good, okay. Next paper is about COCA, Contrastive Captioners are Image Text Foundation
지금까지는 너무 좋았어, 알았어. 다음 논문은 COCA에 관한 것입니다. 대조 캡셔너는 Image Text Foundation입니다.
models. COCA combines the contrastive training and generative training together.
모델. COCA는 대조 훈련과 생성 훈련을 결합합니다.
So recall BLIP for each image text pair. The downside of BLIP is the pre-training requires
따라서 각 이미지 텍스트 쌍에 대해 BLIP을 기억하세요. BLIP의 단점은 사전 훈련이 필요하다는 것입니다.
one forward pass through the region transformer, and then you need like three forward passes
지역 변환기를 통과하는 한 번의 순방향 패스, 그런 다음 세 번의 순방향 패스가 필요합니다.
through the text transformers, which is very not efficient. So COCA wants to
매우 효율적이지 않은 텍스트 변환기를 통해. 그래서 COCA는
have a minimalist design of BLIP to improve the training efficiency.
훈련 효율성을 향상시키기 위해 BLIP의 미니멀한 디자인을 가지고 있습니다.
So what they did is they replaced the text encoder with a new model text encoder,
그래서 그들이 한 일은 텍스트 인코더를 새로운 모델 텍스트 인코더로 교체한 것입니다.
and they changed the bi-directional self-attention to a mass self-attention.
그리고 그들은 양방향 self-attention을 대량 self-attention으로 바꾸었습니다.
And for the text input, they added the classification token at the end. So they want to use the
그리고 텍스트 입력의 경우 마지막에 분류 토큰을 추가했습니다. 그래서 그들은
generated classification token as the embedding of the text and use that to calculate the ITC
텍스트 삽입으로 분류 토큰을 생성하고 이를 사용하여 ITC를 계산합니다.
loss same as before. Because the motivation is like there are so many text encoders.
이전과 같은 손실. 동기는 텍스트 인코더가 너무 많기 때문입니다.
Two encoders, one encoder. It's not efficient. So then their idea is what if we only use the
인코더 2개, 인코더 1개. 효율적이지 않습니다. 그렇다면 그들의 생각은 우리가 단지
encoder? What if we don't use encoder at all? But the problem is if you only use encoder,
인코더? 인코더를 전혀 사용하지 않으면 어떻게 되나요? 하지만 문제는 인코더만 사용하는 경우,
how do you get the embedding of your text? So they append a classification token at the end.
텍스트를 어떻게 삽입하나요? 따라서 끝에 분류 토큰을 추가합니다.
It's a trainable token, and they hope that the output of the classification token can be a good
이는 훈련 가능한 토큰이며 분류 토큰의 출력이 좋은 결과를 얻을 수 있기를 바랍니다.
representation embedding of the whole text. You mean the decoder? Not to see this.
전체 텍스트의 표현 임베딩. 디코더를 말하는 건가요? 이것을 보기 위해서가 아닙니다.
So like the whole text decoder is a trainable encoder, including the classification token.
따라서 전체 텍스트 디코더와 마찬가지로 분류 토큰을 포함하여 훈련 가능한 인코더도 있습니다.
So yeah, this is the COCA architecture. They don't have this in their paper,
네, 이것이 COCA 아키텍처입니다. 그 사람들 신문에는 이런 내용이 없어요.
but I just draw this based on my understanding. So yeah, they use only decoder. The left one
하지만 저는 이것을 제가 이해한 바에 따라 그립니다. 네, 그들은 디코더만 사용합니다. 왼쪽 것
is a unimodal text decoder. They use this to, like I mentioned before, they append the classification
단봉 텍스트 디코더입니다. 앞서 언급한 것처럼 이를 사용하여 분류를 추가합니다.
token at the end. So the output sequence, the last token of the output sequence,
마지막에 토큰. 따라서 출력 시퀀스의 마지막 토큰인 출력 시퀀스는
corresponds to the CIS token. And they use this to calculate ITC loss with the imaging
CIS 토큰에 해당합니다. 그리고 이를 사용하여 이미징으로 ITC 손실을 계산합니다.
encoder. Let's just forget about this part with the imaging encoder. And then the rest of the
인코더. 이미징 인코더를 사용하면 이 부분은 잊어버리세요. 그리고 나머지는
output from the first half of the decoder sends to the second half of the decoder. And then here
디코더의 전반부 출력은 디코더의 후반부로 전송됩니다. 그리고 여기
they have a cross-attention. The signal comes from your image, and then you have your LM loss.
그들은 교차 관심을 가지고 있습니다. 신호는 이미지에서 나오며 LM 손실이 발생합니다.
So yes, they have one very big decoder. They cut them in half. The first part is a unimodal,
그렇습니다. 그들은 매우 큰 디코더를 하나 가지고 있습니다. 그들은 그것들을 반으로 잘랐습니다. 첫 번째 부분은 단일 모드이며,
and the second part is the multimodal. So with this design, for every pair of image attacks,
두 번째 부분은 다중 모드입니다. 따라서 이 설계를 사용하면 모든 이미지 공격 쌍에 대해
image pass through the imaging encoder once, and the attacks pass through the decoder once.
이미지는 이미징 인코더를 한 번 통과하고, 공격은 디코더를 한 번 통과합니다.
Basically, I think it's basically decoder, decoder.
기본적으로는 기본적으로 디코더, 디코더라고 생각합니다.
Yeah, they assign it to the decoder.
네, 디코더에 할당했어요.
It's a decoder. It's a decoder.
디코더입니다. 디코더입니다.
It's a decoder. Because it's causal, causal attention.
디코더입니다. 인과적, 인과적 관심이기 때문입니다.
Oh, it's a cause. It's a cause of attention.
아, 원인이군요. 주목을 받는 이유입니다.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I didn't like this figure. When I read this paper, there's no such figure.
응, 응, 응. 나는 이 그림이 마음에 들지 않았다. 이 글을 읽어보니 그런 인물은 없습니다.
It took me a really long time to understand what's going on. I haven't figured it out.
무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 이해하는 데 정말 오랜 시간이 걸렸습니다. 나는 그것을 이해하지 못했습니다.
Their figure is very high-level.
그들의 수치는 매우 높은 수준입니다.
Yeah, we're at a very high level. But they kind of split one decoder into half,
네, 우리는 매우 높은 수준에 있습니다. 하지만 그들은 하나의 디코더를 반으로 나누었습니다.
one, like the first half way, encoding the text. But it's a decoder that encodes the text.
하나는 전반부와 마찬가지로 텍스트를 인코딩하는 것입니다. 하지만 텍스트를 인코딩하는 디코더입니다.
Then the other part of the decoder takes the input from the image encoder,
그런 다음 디코더의 다른 부분은 이미지 인코더로부터 입력을 받습니다.
so that we don't do the weights of time again. It's already calculated in the ITC,
다시는 시간의 무게를 두지 않도록 말이죠. 이미 ITC에서 계산되어 있고,
and then you just put in everything and do another loss.
그런 다음 모든 것을 투자하고 또 다른 손실을 입습니다.
So this is a very smart design. It's very efficient.
그래서 이것은 매우 똑똑한 디자인입니다. 매우 효율적입니다.
That's about the text decoder parts.
그것은 텍스트 디코더 부분에 관한 것입니다.
And now I'll talk about what they call attentional pullers. I find this is interesting.
이제 나는 그들이 주의를 끄는 사람이라고 부르는 것에 대해 이야기하겠습니다. 나는 이것이 흥미롭다고 생각한다.
So they call it task-specific attentional puller.
그래서 그들은 그것을 작업별 주의력 끌어당김 도구라고 부릅니다.
So this guy is a single multi-hat attention layer with inquiry learnable queries
따라서 이 사람은 학습 가능한 쿼리가 포함된 단일 다중 모자 관심 레이어입니다.
with image encoder output as both the key and value. So the learnable queries is Q,
이미지 인코더 출력을 키와 값으로 사용합니다. 따라서 학습 가능한 쿼리는 Q입니다.
and the output of the image encoder is K and D.
이미지 인코더의 출력은 K와 D입니다.
So why they need this? Because to calculate the ITC loss, you need a 1 by D vector to compare with
그렇다면 왜 이것이 필요한가요? ITC 손실을 계산하려면 다음과 비교할 1 by D 벡터가 필요합니다.
this 1 by D vector. So they set the inquiry to be 1. So then after this attentional pulling,
이것은 1 by D 벡터입니다. 그래서 그들은 조사를 1로 설정했습니다. 그래서 주의를 집중시킨 후에,
this output is 1 by D. And then you can use this output to calculate the ITC.
이 출력은 D에 의해 1입니다. 그리고 이 출력을 사용하여 ITC를 계산할 수 있습니다.
But for this decoder, the cross-attention needs a longer sequence. So in their paper,
하지만 이 디코더의 경우 교차 어텐션에는 더 긴 시퀀스가 ​​필요합니다. 그래서 그들의 논문에서는
they set the inquiry to be 256 for the LN loss. So basically, this is an adapter
그들은 LN 손실에 대해 문의를 256으로 설정했습니다. 기본적으로 이것은 어댑터입니다.
to have different length of sequences for the same image embedded.
삽입된 동일한 이미지에 대해 서로 다른 길이의 시퀀스를 갖습니다.
And the reason why they want this sequence to be longer, because
그리고 그들이 이 시퀀스를 더 길게 원하는 이유는,
the longer it is, the more regional level features you have. It's more like fine graph
길이가 길수록 지역 수준의 기능이 더 많아집니다. 미세한 그래프에 가깝습니다
versus what a 1 by D, it's a global representation of their image features.
1xD와 비교하면 이미지 기능을 전체적으로 표현한 것입니다.
And then the benefits of attentional puller is it's a natural
그리고 주의를 끄는 사람의 이점은 그것이 자연스럽다는 것입니다.
adapter for downstream tasks. For example, for video classification tasks, a single query token
다운스트림 작업을 위한 어댑터. 예를 들어 비디오 분류 작업의 경우 단일 쿼리 토큰
is learned to weight outputs of all tokens of like the different frames.
다른 프레임과 같은 모든 토큰의 출력에 가중치를 부여하는 방법을 학습합니다.
So here we have six frames, each frame you can get out like many different patches.
여기에는 6개의 프레임이 있으며, 각 프레임은 다양한 패치처럼 가져올 수 있습니다.
And you concatenate them together, you use your attentional puller to pull them into
그리고 당신은 그것들을 서로 연결하고 주의를 끄는 도구를 사용하여 그것들을 끌어당깁니다.
a single 1 by D vector. And then they also find that like using attentional puller
단일 1 x D 벡터. 그리고 그들은 또한 주의를 끄는 도구를 사용하는 것과 같은 것을 발견합니다.
enhance the frozen feature evaluation, because linear probing struggles to accurately measure
선형 프로빙은 정확하게 측정하는 데 어려움을 겪기 때문에 동결된 특징 평가를 향상시킵니다.
the learned representations. However, using a learning a new puller to aggregate features
학습된 표현. 그러나 새로운 풀러 학습을 사용하여 기능을 집계합니다.
enables the model to obtain a stronger performance as a frozen encoder.
모델이 고정 인코더로서 더 강력한 성능을 얻을 수 있도록 해줍니다.
It can also be benefit, it can also benefit to multitask problems that share the same frozen
그것은 또한 이익이 될 수 있으며, 동일한 정지 상태를 공유하는 다중 작업 문제에도 이익이 될 수 있습니다.
image encoder, but different tasks specific has.
이미지 인코더가 있지만 특정 작업에는 다른 작업이 있습니다.
So the pre-training of COCA, the loss function is a combination of ITC and LM. And they have
따라서 COCA의 사전 훈련, 손실 함수는 ITC와 LM의 조합입니다. 그리고 그들은
this reading error parameters here. Empirically to find a larger loss weight is better.
이 읽기 오류 매개변수는 여기에 있습니다. 경험적으로는 더 큰 손실 가중치를 찾는 것이 더 좋습니다.
So they set the LM over LM ITC to be 2 to 1. Their explanation is the ITC loss can be interpreted
그래서 그들은 LM 대비 LM ITC를 2:1로 설정했습니다. 그들의 설명은 ITC 손실이 해석될 수 있다는 것입니다.
as a special case of the generative approach applied on image when the vocabulary is just a set
어휘가 단지 집합일 때 이미지에 적용되는 생성적 접근 방식의 특별한 경우
of all your captions. The two parts of the decoder number of layers are the same,
당신의 모든 캡션 중. 디코더 레이어 수의 두 부분은 동일합니다.
and they have a very huge data set, it's like 4.8 billion. And then the evaluation of COCA,
그들은 48억 개에 달하는 매우 거대한 데이터 세트를 보유하고 있습니다. 그리고 COCA에 대한 평가는,
it outperforms the low encoder model and decoder decoder model and specialized
이는 낮은 인코더 모델 및 디코더 디코더 모델보다 성능이 뛰어나며 전문화되었습니다.
SOHA models on 12 different benchmarks. I think this is because the data set is really,
12가지 벤치마크의 SOHA 모델. 제 생각에는 데이터 세트가 실제로
really large. In this part, we're going to talk about the training scaling up.
정말 크다. 이번 시간에는 훈련 규모 확장에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
And in this part, there's only one paper, SIGLIP Sigma loss for language image pre-training.
그리고 이 부분에는 언어 이미지 사전 훈련을 위한 SIGLIP Sigma loss라는 논문이 하나만 있습니다.
This paper is focusing on scaling up the training with Sigma loss.
이 문서에서는 시그마 손실을 사용하여 훈련을 확장하는 데 중점을 두고 있습니다.
Now let's look at the background and motivation of SIGLIP. We know that a lot of work uses the
이제 SIGLIP의 탄생 배경과 동기를 살펴보자. 우리는 많은 작업에서
contrasted pre-training because contrasted pre-training itself is a weak supervision task,
대조 사전 훈련 자체가 약한 감독 작업이기 때문에 대조 사전 훈련
and it can align the representation space for images and texts, just like what we do in CLIPPET
CLIPPET에서와 마찬가지로 이미지와 텍스트의 표현 공간을 정렬할 수 있습니다.
align. And contrasted pre-training always use the batch level softmax-based contrastive loss,
맞추다. 그리고 대조 사전 훈련은 항상 배치 수준 소프트맥스 기반 대조 손실을 사용합니다.
which does the pairwise similarity scores across all images and then for all texts.
모든 이미지와 모든 텍스트에 대해 쌍별 유사성 점수를 계산합니다.
To some extent, the softmax-based contrastive loss is numerically unstable, and the stabilization
소프트맥스 기반 대비 손실은 어느 정도 수치적으로 불안정하며, 안정화는
process always requires additional paths over the full batch.
프로세스에는 항상 전체 배치에 대한 추가 경로가 필요합니다.
So in this paper, they propose a single pairwise Sigma loss for language image pre-training, SIGLIP.
따라서 본 논문에서는 언어 이미지 사전 훈련을 위한 단일 쌍별 시그마 손실인 SIGLIP을 제안합니다.
Unlike the contrastive learning with a softmax normalization, the Sigma loss operates solely
소프트맥스 정규화를 사용한 대조 학습과 달리 시그마 손실은 단독으로 작동합니다.
on image text pairs and doesn't require a global view of the pairwise similarities for normalization.
이미지 텍스트 쌍에 대한 것이며 정규화를 위해 쌍별 유사성에 대한 전역 보기가 필요하지 않습니다.
The Sigma loss simultaneously allows further scaling of the batch size while also performing
시그마 손실을 통해 동시에 배치 크기를 추가로 확장하는 동시에 수행할 수도 있습니다.
better at smaller batch sizes. Now we first review the wide-used softmax-based contrastive loss,
더 작은 배치 크기에서 더 좋습니다. 이제 먼저 널리 사용되는 소프트맥스 기반 대비 손실을 검토합니다.
given a mini-batch of image text pairs and the contrastive learning objective encourages
이미지 텍스트 쌍의 미니 배치와 대조 학습 목표가 주어지면
embeddings of matching pairs to align with each other while pushing embeddings of unmatched
일치하는 쌍의 임베딩을 서로 정렬하고 일치하지 않는 임베딩을 푸시합니다.
pairs apart. So for practical use, it's always assumed that for each images and the text associated
짝을 이룬다. 따라서 실제 사용을 위해 항상 각 이미지와 관련 텍스트에 대해
with a different image is not related to the image in vice versa. And we're going to show
다른 이미지를 가진 것은 그 반대의 경우에도 이미지와 관련이 없습니다. 그리고 우리는 보여줄 것입니다
that this assumption is kind of noisy and imperfect. Specifically, when using the softmax loss to
이 가정은 다소 시끄럽고 불완전합니다. 특히, 소프트맥스 손실을 사용하여
formalize this objective over here, an image model F and a text model G are trained to minimize
여기서 이 목표를 공식화하면 이미지 모델 F와 텍스트 모델 G가 최소화되도록 훈련됩니다.
the following objective as in this equation, where X and Y are the normalized embeddings for text and
이 방정식에서와 같이 다음 목표를 달성합니다. 여기서 X와 Y는 텍스트에 대한 정규화된 임베딩이고
image respectively. And we note that due to the asymmetry of the softmax loss, the normalization
각각 이미지. 그리고 우리는 소프트맥스 손실의 비대칭성으로 인해 정규화가
is independently performed two times across images and across text. That is the denominator of the
이미지와 텍스트에 걸쳐 독립적으로 두 번 수행됩니다. 그것이 바로 의 분모이다.
softmax function. And we also have a scalar T, which is a weight hyperparameter in this model.
소프트맥스 함수. 그리고 이 모델에는 가중치 하이퍼파라미터인 스칼라 T도 있습니다.
The normalization of global batch data used in contrastive training results in excessive
대조 훈련에 사용되는 전역 배치 데이터의 정규화는 과도한 결과를 초래합니다.
communication overhead and manual usage. And contrastive training utilizes typically data
통신 오버헤드 및 수동 사용. 그리고 대조 훈련은 일반적으로 데이터를 활용합니다.
parallelism and computing the loss when data is split across different devices always requires
병렬성과 데이터가 여러 장치에 분할될 때 손실을 계산하려면 항상 다음이 필요합니다.
gathering all embeddings with expensive all caddlers. And more importantly, the materialization
값비싼 모든 캐들러로 모든 임베딩을 수집합니다. 그리고 무엇보다 중요한 것은 구체화이다.
of memory intensive batch size level matrix of pairwise similarities. So instead of the softmax
쌍별 유사성의 메모리 집약적 배치 크기 수준 행렬. 그래서 소프트맥스 대신
base contrastive loss, they propose the simpler alternative that doesn't require computing the
기본 대비 손실을 계산할 필요가 없는 더 간단한 대안을 제안합니다.
global normalization factors. Over here, we're going to investigate a segment loss
전역 정규화 요인. 여기서는 세그먼트 손실을 조사하겠습니다.
in details. For example, the sigmoid loss is particularly amenable to a memory-efficient
자세히. 예를 들어, 시그모이드 손실은 특히 메모리 효율적인 방식에 적합합니다.
fast and numerically stable implementation that alleviates both these issues. And the sigmoid
이러한 문제를 모두 완화하는 빠르고 수치적으로 안정적인 구현입니다. 그리고 시그모이드
base loss processes every image text pair independently, effectively turning the learning
기본 손실은 모든 이미지 텍스트 쌍을 독립적으로 처리하여 학습을 효과적으로 전환합니다.
problem into the standard binary classification on the data sets of all pair combinations
모든 쌍 조합의 데이터 세트에 대한 표준 이진 분류 문제
with the positive labels for the matching pairs and negative labels for all other pairs.
일치하는 쌍에는 양수 레이블을, 다른 모든 쌍에는 음수 레이블을 사용합니다.
And it's defined as over here, where Z actually is the label for a given image and text input,
그리고 이것은 여기에 다음과 같이 정의되어 있습니다. 여기서 Z는 실제로 주어진 이미지와 텍스트 입력에 대한 레이블입니다.
she calls to one if they're paired and equal to negative one otherwise.
그녀는 쌍을 이루는 경우 하나를 호출하고 그렇지 않으면 음수와 동일합니다.
Here I draw the figures to show how the loss function changes.
여기서는 손실 함수가 어떻게 변하는지 보여주기 위해 그림을 그립니다.
Take an example of a single pair. If it's the positive pair, the loss value will get smaller
단일 쌍의 예를 들어 보겠습니다. 양수 쌍인 경우 손실 값이 작아집니다.
as the cosine similarity of the pair gets to one. And if it's the negative pair, the loss value
쌍의 코사인 유사성은 1이 됩니다. 그리고 음수 쌍인 경우 손실 값은
will get smaller as the cosine similarity of the pair gets to zero. So the model will be optimized
쌍의 코사인 유사성이 0이 될수록 작아집니다. 그러면 모델이 최적화될 것입니다.
to encourage embeddings of matching pairs to align with each other while pushing embeddings of
임베딩을 푸시하는 동안 일치하는 쌍의 임베딩이 서로 정렬되도록 장려합니다.
unmatched pairs apart. Now we're going to talk about the efficient loss implementation
타의 추종을 불허하는 쌍이 떨어져 있습니다. 이제 효율적인 손실 구현에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
mentioned in this paper, which can be demonstrated by this example with only three devices and a
이 문서에서는 세 개의 장치와 한 개의 장치만으로 이 예를 통해 설명할 수 있습니다.
global batch size of 12. Actually, the no or gathers and at any point in time, only the bright
글로벌 배치 크기는 12입니다. 실제로는 없음 또는 수집 및 어느 시점에서든 밝은
yellow square with a size of four by four is materialized in memory. Now we can see the stage
메모리에는 4 x 4 크기의 노란색 사각형이 구현됩니다. 이제 무대가 보이네
one, the stage a, initially each device holds four image and four text representations.
첫 번째, 단계 a에서는 처음에 각 장치가 4개의 이미지와 4개의 텍스트 표현을 보유합니다.
And each device needs to see the representations from other devices to calculate the full loss
그리고 각 장치는 전체 손실을 계산하기 위해 다른 장치의 표현을 확인해야 합니다.
finally. And we have to know that within the device one, for example, for I1, we need to
마지막으로. 그리고 우리는 예를 들어 I1의 경우 장치 내에서 다음을 수행해야 한다는 것을 알아야 합니다.
calculate the loss between I1 and T1 and T12 finally. And we can go to stage B. On stage B,
마지막으로 I1과 T1 및 T12 사이의 손실을 계산합니다. 그리고 B단계로 갈 수 있습니다. B단계에서는
they each compute the component of the loss for their representations, which includes the positive,
그들은 각각 자신의 표현에 대한 손실 구성 요소를 계산합니다. 여기에는 긍정적인 내용이 포함됩니다.
which means that each device calculates the loss locally. For example, in this figure,
이는 각 장치가 로컬에서 손실을 계산한다는 의미입니다. 예를 들어, 이 그림에서는
now we can compute the loss between I1, I4 and T1 to T4. And now we can go to stage C.
이제 I1, I4 및 T1에서 T4 사이의 손실을 계산할 수 있습니다. 이제 C단계로 넘어갈 수 있습니다.
On stage C, actually, texts can be swept across the devices. So device one now has I1 to 4
실제로 C 단계에서는 텍스트가 여러 장치에 걸쳐 스윕될 수 있습니다. 따라서 장치 1에는 이제 I1부터 4까지가 있습니다.
and T5 to 8, etc. And the new loss is computed and accumulated with the previous.
그리고 T5 ~ 8 등. 그리고 새로운 손실은 이전 손실과 함께 계산되고 누적됩니다.
For example, now we look at this figure on stage C, because device one now has the T5 to T8,
예를 들어 이제 C 단계에서 이 그림을 살펴보겠습니다. 왜냐하면 장치 1에는 이제 T5 ~ T8이 있기 때문입니다.
we can compute the loss between I1 to 4 and T5 to 8. Now we're only left with the loss function
I1~4와 T5~8 사이의 손실을 계산할 수 있습니다. 이제 손실 함수만 남았습니다.
between I1 to 4 and T9 to 12. So on stage D, this repeats till every image and text pair
I1에서 4와 T9에서 12 사이입니다. 따라서 D단계에서는 모든 이미지와 텍스트 쌍이 나타날 때까지 반복됩니다.
have interacted. For example, device one has the loss of I1 to 4 and T1 to 12. And we can do a
상호작용을 했습니다. 예를 들어, 장치 1에는 I1에서 4, T1에서 12의 손실이 있습니다. 그리고 우리는 다음을 수행할 수 있습니다.
final cross-device sum brings everything together. For example, on stage D, finally, we can compute
최종 교차 장치 합계는 모든 것을 하나로 모읍니다. 예를 들어, D 단계에서는 마지막으로 다음을 계산할 수 있습니다.
the loss between I1 to 4 and T9 to 12. And everything is cleared now. And now we can finally
I1에서 4까지와 T9에서 12 사이의 손실. 이제 모든 것이 지워졌습니다. 그리고 이제 우리는 마침내
do a final cross-device sum to turn all of this sum into a single scalar for the loss function.
이 모든 합계를 손실 함수에 대한 단일 스칼라로 변환하기 위해 최종 교차 장치 합계를 수행합니다.
Now let's look at the experiments. In this paper, they train a model siglit based on lit
이제 실험을 살펴보겠습니다. 이 논문에서는 조명을 기반으로 모델 시그릿을 훈련합니다.
model with sigmy loss. And the sigmy loss all performs this softmax loss significantly with
시그미 손실이 있는 모델. 그리고 시그미 손실은 모두 이 소프트맥스 손실을 다음과 같이 크게 수행합니다.
small batch sizes and performs similarly at larger batch sizes. Particularly, they successfully
배치 크기가 작으며 더 큰 배치 크기에서도 유사한 성능을 발휘합니다. 특히 그들은 성공적으로
trained a siglit model with up to one million batch size, which shows that the sigmy loss
배치 크기가 최대 100만 개인 시그릿 모델을 훈련했는데, 이는 시그미 손실이 다음과 같다는 것을 보여줍니다.
advantages on memory saving. And actually with only four TVU V4 chips, they train a siglit
메모리 절약의 이점. 그리고 실제로 TVU V4 칩 4개만으로 시그릿을 훈련합니다.
model that achieves good image net zero shot accuracy in two days. And they also train a model
이틀 만에 좋은 이미지 넷 제로 샷 정확도를 달성하는 모델입니다. 그리고 그들은 또한 모델을 훈련시킵니다.
siglit based on clip model with sigmy loss. And both sigmy loss and softmax loss saturate at a
시그미 손실이 있는 클립 모델을 기반으로 한 시그릿. 그리고 시그미 손실과 소프트맥스 손실은 모두
reasonable batch size, while the peak of the sigmy loss comes earlier and slightly outperforms
합리적인 배치 크기, 시그미 손실의 정점이 더 일찍 나타나고 약간 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
the peak of the softmax loss. A very large batch size hurts both losses, which we can see from this
소프트맥스 손실의 정점. 매우 큰 배치 크기는 두 가지 손실 모두에 해를 끼치며, 이를 통해 확인할 수 있습니다.
figure. And now we're going to talk about the experiment of label noise robinus. Actually,
수치. 이제 라벨 노이즈 로비누스(Labinus) 실험에 대해 이야기하겠습니다. 실제로,
prior works demonstrated improved robinus against label noise when using the sigmy loss for classification
이전 연구에서는 분류를 위해 시그미 손실을 사용할 때 라벨 노이즈에 대한 개선된 로비누스가 입증되었습니다.
models. And this property would be particularly useful here in the face of the famously noisy
모델. 그리고 이 속성은 여기에서 시끄러운 것으로 유명한 상황에서 특히 유용할 것입니다.
nature of popular large scale image text datasets. Here we can see the sigmy training
널리 사용되는 대규모 이미지 텍스트 데이터세트의 성격. 여기서 우리는 시그미 훈련을 볼 수 있습니다
increases the robinus to data noise and titles show that the type of corruption applied and x-axis
로비누스를 데이터 노이즈로 증가시키고 제목은 적용된 손상 유형과 x축을 보여줍니다.
show the probability with which they're applied. With increasing corruption severity, the models
적용될 확률을 보여줍니다. 부패 심각도가 높아짐에 따라 모델은
trained with sigmy loss for large scale dataset achieve very good performance over the corresponding
대규모 데이터 세트에 대해 시그미 손실로 훈련되어 해당 데이터 세트에 비해 매우 좋은 성능을 달성했습니다.
softmax baseline. Finally, we can do some conclusion for the siglip in this paper.
소프트맥스 기준. 마지막으로, 우리는 이 논문에서 siglip에 대해 몇 가지 결론을 내릴 수 있습니다.
They conducted a study on two language image portraying instances that use the sigmy loss
시그미 손실을 사용하는 사례를 묘사하는 두 가지 언어 이미지에 대한 연구를 수행했습니다.
siglit and siglip and that their results demonstrate that the sigmy loss performs better than the
siglit과 siglip의 결과는 sigmy loss가 sigmy loss보다 성능이 더 우수하다는 것을 보여줍니다.
softmax baseline, particularly for small training batch sizes. And this loss function is also
특히 소규모 교육 배치 크기의 경우 소프트맥스 기준선입니다. 그리고 이 손실 함수는 또한
more memory efficient which allows larger trained batch sizes without requiring additional resources
추가 리소스 없이 더 큰 훈련된 배치 크기를 허용하는 메모리 효율성이 더 높습니다.
like computer resources or timer resources. Finally, this is the last paper we show today
컴퓨터 리소스나 타이머 리소스와 같습니다. 드디어 오늘 보여드리는 마지막 논문입니다
and it's also a good ending to the paper presentation part today. In this paper presentation part,
그리고 오늘 논문 발표 부분도 잘 마무리했습니다. 이번 논문발표부분에서는
we first introduce how to improve the performance of VL tasks by improving the performance of
먼저 VL 작업의 성능을 향상하여 VL 작업의 성능을 향상시키는 방법을 소개합니다.
object detection. And then we talked about designing larger models and applying larger
물체 감지. 그런 다음 더 큰 모델을 설계하고 더 큰 모델을 적용하는 방법에 대해 이야기했습니다.
amounts of data to improve the performance of VL tasks at scale. Later, we introduce more
대규모로 VL 작업의 성능을 향상시키기 위한 데이터 양. 나중에 더 소개하자면
complicated models with decoder architecture to adapt to more VL tasks from a generation perspective.
세대 관점에서 더 많은 VL 작업에 적응하기 위한 디코더 아키텍처를 갖춘 복잡한 모델입니다.
And finally, we introduce how to replace softmax with sigmy function to make
그리고 마지막으로 Softmax를 sigmy 함수로 대체하는 방법을 소개합니다.
fast training and huge batch size possible, just preparing for future work that may face
빠른 훈련과 대규모 배치 크기 가능, 앞으로 직면할 수 있는 작업에 대비하기만 하면 됩니다.
larger data volumes and more model parameters. So now we can go to the complete summary of today's
더 큰 데이터 볼륨과 더 많은 모델 매개변수. 이제 오늘의 전체 요약을 살펴보겠습니다.
presentation. So to summarize what we have covered today, we covered four different losses.
프레젠테이션. 오늘 우리가 다룬 내용을 요약하자면, 네 가지 손실을 다루었습니다.
The first one is the contrastive loss which has different variations. The most common one is the
첫 번째는 다양한 변형을 갖는 대조 손실입니다. 가장 일반적인 것은
image text contrastive loss, ITC in short. It's a sum of the image to text and text to image info
이미지 텍스트 대비 손실, 줄여서 ITC입니다. 이미지를 텍스트로, 텍스트를 이미지 정보로 합친 것입니다.
and CE loss to contrast paired text against others in the sampled batch. Models that use ITC loss
샘플링된 배치의 다른 텍스트와 쌍을 이루는 텍스트를 대조하기 위한 CE 손실. ITC 손실을 사용하는 모델
includes a clip and blip. And then we've also seen sigmoid loss which is used in sig lip
클립과 글이 포함되어 있습니다. 그리고 시그모이드 손실(sigmoid loss)도 보았습니다. 이는 시그립(sig lip)에 사용됩니다.
as a binary classification of all pair combinations. And then we have also seen
모든 쌍 조합의 이진 분류로 사용됩니다. 그리고 우리도 봤어요
the binary classification to predict whether text image and tag triplet contains the original tag
텍스트 이미지와 태그 삼중항에 원본 태그가 포함되어 있는지 예측하는 이진 분류
or polluted tag. This is used by, for example, oscar. But I think this is more, well, I mean,
또는 오염된 태그. 예를 들어 oscar에서 사용됩니다. 하지만 제 생각에는 이것이 그 이상이라고 생각합니다.
oscar calls it the contrast of loss, but I think this is more similar to the image text matching loss.
오스카는 이를 손실의 대비라고 부르는데, 내 생각에는 이것이 손실의 이미지 텍스트 일치와 더 유사하다고 생각합니다.
So image text matching loss is a binary classification to predict whether an image text pair
따라서 이미지 텍스트 일치 손실은 이미지 텍스트 쌍이 일치하는지 여부를 예측하는 이진 분류입니다.
is matched or a matched. This is used in blip. And then we've also seen the language modeling loss.
일치하거나 일치합니다. 이것은 블립에서 사용됩니다. 그리고 우리는 언어 모델링 손실도 보았습니다.
This is the same loss as used in chat GPT. So this is a generative task to produce textual
이는 채팅 GPT에서 사용된 것과 동일한 손실입니다. 따라서 이것은 텍스트를 생성하는 생성 작업입니다.
descriptions in an auto regressive manner given an image. Again, blip uses this loss.
이미지가 주어지면 자동 회귀 방식으로 설명합니다. 다시 말하지만, blip은 이 손실을 사용합니다.
And then we have also covered mask language modeling loss.
그리고 마스크 언어 모델링 손실도 다루었습니다.
This loss predicts the text tokens based on surrounding text tokens and the image features.
이 손실은 주변 텍스트 토큰과 이미지 특징을 기반으로 텍스트 토큰을 예측합니다.
For example, oscar and minville both uses this loss.
예를 들어, oscar와 minville은 모두 이 손실을 사용합니다.
And then we'll look at the models from the architecture perspective. The first family
그런 다음 아키텍처 관점에서 모델을 살펴보겠습니다. 첫 번째 가족
we have is uni encoder based multi models. The first one is oscar.
우리는 유니 인코더 기반의 다중 모델을 가지고 있습니다. 첫 번째는 오스카입니다.
Oscar fees the sequence of tags, tags and image regions embeddings to BERT. And then
Oscar는 BERT에 일련의 태그, 태그 및 이미지 영역 삽입 비용을 지불합니다. 그런 다음
its semantic alignments between tags and images using object tags. It uses the ITC loss and the ML
객체 태그를 사용하여 태그와 이미지 간의 의미 정렬. ITC 손실과 ML을 사용합니다.
loss. We've also covered minville. It improves oscar with a more powerful object detection model.
손실. 민빌도 다루었습니다. 더욱 강력한 객체 감지 모델로 오스카를 개선합니다.
It also introduced a three-way contrastive loss and then uses the same MLM loss as oscar.
또한 3방향 대비 손실을 도입한 다음 오스카와 동일한 MLM 손실을 사용합니다.
So the table at the bottom shows the the evaluation of two
그래서 하단의 표는 두 사람의 평가를 보여줍니다.
uni encoder based models on different tasks. The benchmarks in blue are the understanding
다양한 작업에 대한 uni 인코더 기반 모델. 파란색 벤치마크는 이해도입니다.
task and then the benchmarks in orange is the generative tasks. And we can see minville out
작업이고 주황색 벤치마크는 생성 작업입니다. 그리고 우리는 민빌이 밖을 볼 수 있습니다
performs oscar on most of the tasks. Not surprisingly because one uses a more powerful object detection
대부분의 작업에서 오스카를 수행합니다. 더 강력한 객체 감지 기능을 사용하기 때문에 놀랄 것도 없습니다.
model and two it just uses more image text pairs.
모델과 두 개는 더 많은 이미지 텍스트 쌍을 사용합니다.
And then next we also covered dual encoder based models. They include clip, align and siglip.
그리고 다음에는 듀얼 인코더 기반 모델도 다루었습니다. 여기에는 클립, 정렬 및 시그립이 포함됩니다.
So clip introduced a learnable text encoder to encode freeform text. It uses ITC loss
그래서 Clip은 자유 형식 텍스트를 인코딩하기 위해 학습 가능한 텍스트 인코더를 도입했습니다. ITC 손실을 사용합니다.
and then align based on clip is sacrifice quality to gain quantity. So it scaled up the
그런 다음 클립을 기준으로 정렬하면 수량을 얻기 위해 품질이 희생됩니다. 그래서 규모를 키웠습니다.
corpus to 1.8 billion. It extends the dataset to multilingual setting to train align
총량은 18억 개로 늘어났습니다. 학습 정렬을 위해 데이터 세트를 다국어 설정으로 확장합니다.
multilingual. And then siglip changed the softmax based ITC loss to a sigmoid based loss.
다국어. 그런 다음 siglip은 소프트맥스 기반 ITC 손실을 시그모이드 기반 손실로 변경했습니다.
The advantage of this loss is it's more memory efficient, it's faster and it improves the
이러한 손실의 장점은 메모리 효율성이 더 높고 속도가 더 빠르며 성능이 향상된다는 것입니다.
numerically stable implementation. So the table below shows the evaluation of these three models.
수치적으로 안정적인 구현. 그래서 아래 표는 이 세 가지 모델에 대한 평가를 보여줍니다.
As we can see siglip out performs the other two and it also uses a lot a lot bigger dataset.
보시다시피 siglip out은 다른 두 가지를 수행하며 훨씬 더 큰 데이터 세트를 사용합니다.
It's like 40 billion which is insane. And then we also covered encoder decoder based family.
400억이면 미친짓이네요. 그런 다음 인코더 디코더 기반 제품군도 다루었습니다.
This includes blip and coca. So blip added the natural language generation capabilities to
여기에는 블립과 코카가 포함됩니다. 그래서 blip은 자연어 생성 기능을 추가했습니다.
the previous models. It uses ITCLM and ITM loss. So the main motivation behind blip is quality
이전 모델. ITCLM 및 ITM 손실을 사용합니다. 따라서 Blip의 주요 동기는 품질입니다.
also matters. We need to improve the text quality by bootstrapping the text. And for coca it takes
또한 중요합니다. 텍스트를 부트스트래핑하여 텍스트 품질을 개선해야 합니다. 그리고 코카의 경우에는
a minimalist design of blip. It reduces the number of forward passes through transform blocks.
미니멀한 디자인의 블립. 변환 블록을 통한 정방향 패스 수를 줄입니다.
And coca reduces the loss down to just ITC and LM loss. And then coca is trained with a lot bigger
그리고 코카는 손실을 ITC와 LM 손실로 줄입니다. 그리고 코카는 훨씬 더 큰 규모로 훈련됩니다.
corpus than blip. So the table below compares these two models. As we can see coca used a lot
블립보다 코퍼스. 그래서 아래 표에서는 이 두 모델을 비교합니다. 보시다시피 코카는 많이 사용됩니다
bigger corpus than blip. But I mean on six of the tasks it all performs blip on four of them.
블립보다 더 큰 말뭉치. 하지만 내 말은 6가지 작업 중 4가지 작업이 모두 수행된다는 의미입니다.
So yeah that's it. Thank you everyone for listening.
그래, 그게 다야. 들어주신 모든 분들께 감사드립니다.